<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Coiba Island howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Central America	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>CoibaIslandhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Coiba Island howler (Alouatta coibensis) is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Panama. Although the Coiba Island howler is generally recognized as a separate species, mitochondrial DNA testing is inconclusive as to whether it is actually a subspecies of the mantled howler. The reason for treating it as a separate species is the dermal ridges of its hands and feet differ from those of the mantled howler. A. c. coibensis is smaller than other Central American howler monkeys and has duller pelage than the Azuero howler, Alouatta coibensis trabeata.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Mantled howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Central America, South America	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Mantledhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The mantled howler (Alouatta palliata), or golden-mantled howling monkey, is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, from Central and South America. It is one of the monkey species most often seen and heard in the wild in Central America. It takes its 'mantled' name from the long guard hairs on its sides. The mantled howler is one of the largest Central American monkeys, and males can weigh up to 9.8 kg (22 lb). It is the only Central American monkey that eats large quantities of leaves; it has several adaptations to this folivorous diet. Since leaves are difficult to digest and provide less energy than most foods, the mantled howler spends the majority of each day resting and sleeping. The male mantled howler has an enlarged hyoid bone, a hollow bone near the vocal cords, which amplifies the calls made by the male, and is the reason for the name 'howler'. Howling allows the monkeys to locate each other without expending energy on moving or risking physical confrontation. The mantled howler lives in groups that can have over 40 members, although groups are usually smaller. Most mantled howlers of both sexes are evicted from the group they were born in upon reaching sexual maturity, resulting in most adult group members being unrelated. The most dominant male, the alpha male, gets preference for food and resting places, and mates with most of the receptive females. The mantled howler is important to the rainforest ecology as a seed disperser and germinator. Although it is affected by deforestation, it is able to adapt better than other species, due to its ability to feed on abundant leaves and its ability to live in a limited amount of space.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Guatemalan black howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Central America	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Guatemalanblackhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Guatemalan black howler, or Yucatan black howler, (Alouatta pigra) is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, from Central America. It is found in Belize, Guatemala and Mexico, in and near the Yucatan Peninsula. It lives in evergreen, semideciduous and lowland rain forests. It is also known as the baboon in Belize, although it is not closely related to the baboons in Africa.The Guatemalan black howler is the largest of the howler monkey species and one of the largest of the New World monkeys. Guatemalan black howler males are larger than those of any other Central American monkey species. On average, males weigh 11.4 kg (25 lb) and females weigh 6.4 kg (14 lb). The body is between 521 and 639 mm (20.5 and 25.2 in) in length, excluding the tail.[6] The tail is between 590 and 690 mm (23 and 27 in) long. Adults of both sexes have long, black hair and a prehensile tail, while infants have brown fur. Males over four months old have white scrotums. The Guatemalan black howler shares several adaptations with other species of howler monkey that allow it to pursue a folivorous diet (mostly leaves). Its molars have high shearing crests, to help it eat the leaves, and the male of the species has an enlarged hyoid bone near the vocal cords. This hyoid bone amplifies the male howler's calls, allowing it to locate other males without expending much energy, which is important, since leaves are a low-energy food. Howling occurs primarily at dawn and at dusk.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Red-handed howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>RedhandedHowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The red-handed howler (Alouatta belzebul) is a vulnerable species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey. It is endemic to Brazil, found in the southeastern Amazon and disjunctly in the Atlantic Forest between Rio Grande do Norte and Sergipe. Considerable taxonomic confusion has surrounded this species. Until 2001, most authorities included the Amazon black howler as a subspecies (or simply a taxonomically insignificant variation) of the red-handed howler, though its distinction had already been pointed out much earlier. The red-handed howler remained variable in ecology, colour and pattern of the fur, shape of the cranium, and shape of the hyoid bone (of great importance in the voice of the howler monkeys; a likely isolating mechanism between the species), but a geographical pattern was not clear, resulting in it being treated as a monotypic species. In 2006, a major review of the Brazilian members of the genus Alouatta was able to match some of the variations to geography (though further study was recommended), resulting in the recognition of the Spix's red-handed howler and Maranhão red-handed howler as species separate from the red-handed howler. Even with these as separate species, the colour and pattern of the fur of the red-handed howler remains variable. Most adults are black with reddish-brown hands, feet and distal part of their tails, but some are entirely black (resembling the Amazon black howler), reddish (resembling the red howlers) or somewhere in between.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Brown howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil and Argentina	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Brownhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The brown howler (Alouatta guariba), also known as brown howler monkey, is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey that lives in forests in southeastern Brazil and far northeastern Argentina (Misiones). It lives in groups of two to 11 individuals. Despite the name 'brown howler', it is notably variable in colour, with some individuals appearing largely reddish-orange or black. The two subspecies are: Northern brown howler (A. g. guariba), listed as critically endangered and Southern brown howler (A. g. clamitans). The brown howler lives in the Atlantic forest in South America. The region spreads through the Brazilian states of Bahia and Espírito Santo through Rio Grande do Sul, and Misiones in Argentina.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Guyanan red howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Suriname, Guyana, Trinidad, French Guiana, Venezuela and Brazil.	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Guyananredhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Guyanan red howler (Alouatta macconnelli) is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, native to Suriname, Guyana, Trinidad, French Guiana, Venezuela and Brazil.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Amazon black howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Amazonblackhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Amazon black howler (Alouatta nigerrima) is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, endemic to the south-central Amazon in Brazil. Until 2001, most authorities included it as a subspecies (or simply a taxonomically insignificant variation) of the red-handed howler, though its distinction had already been pointed out much earlier. As suggested by its name, it typically appears entirely black.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Bolivian red howler	</Name>
    <Location>	Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Bolivianredhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Bolivian red howler (Alouatta sara) is a species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Bolivia. It can be found in rain forests, including riverine and seasonally flooded forests. The adult Bolivian red howler has a well-built body that is capable of attaining a maximum body length. Red howler monkeys have a muscular, prehensile tail that enables them to grasp branches or even swing from them. The males are about 20.6 -22.4 inches in height and weigh about 13-17 lbs. The females are a bit smaller at only about 18.4- 19.6 inches and 10-14 lbs.in weight. Their arms and legs are long. The howler hands are strong and dexterous. They feed mostly on leaves and they also enjoy nuts, seeds, fruit, and flowers.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Venezuelan red howler	</Name>
    <Location>	 Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Venezuelanredhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Venezuelan red howler (Alouatta seniculus) is a South American species of howler monkey, a type of New World monkey, found in the western Amazon Basin in Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Brazil. The population in the Santa Cruz Department in Bolivia was split off as a separate species, the Bolivian red howler, in 1986, and more recently, splitting off the population in northeastern South America and Trinidad as the Guyanan red howler has occurred. All howler monkeys belong to the family Atelidae and the infraorder Platyrrhini (New World monkeys). Sexual dimorphism in this species is small; males range from 49–72 cm and females from 46–57 cm long. The males weigh 5.4-9 kg, while females weigh 4.2–7 kg. It has a long prehensile tail of 49–75 cm. The tail is covered with fur except for the last third of the underside, which allows it to grab branches. The color of both males and females is a deep reddish-brown, and the color shade changes with age. Their faces are surrounded by fur and they have stubby noses. The jawbone of the red howler monkey is large, especially the body of the mandible. The position of the foramen magnum is very posterior to make way for the expanded jaw and enlarged hyoid bone. Howler monkeys also have an inflated bulla, which is the bony encasement of the middle ear. This makes them an exception among other New World monkeys. The diurnal Alouatta seniculus is an arboreal primate, so it spends much of its time high in the canopy. Its preferred method of locomotion is quadrupedal walking with minimal leaping. Its long, prehensile tail also assists it by providing both support and grasping abilities. In addition, its hands and feet have a grasping pattern that allows it to better move about in the trees. This can be seen by the wide separation of the second and third digits of the hand.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black howler	</Name>
    <Location>	 Argentina, eastern Bolivia, eastern and southern Brazil, and Paraguay.	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackhowler.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black howler (Alouatta caraya) (also known as black-and-gold howler) is a species of howler monkey, a large New World monkey, from northeastern Argentina, eastern Bolivia, eastern and southern Brazil, and Paraguay. Together with the brown howler, it is the southernmost member of the Alouatta genus. Only the adult male is black; adult females and juveniles of both genders are overall whitish to yellowish-buff. However, variations occur even among the adult males; some have patches of reddish-brown or buff fur. They live in groups of three to 19 individuals (usually seven to 9). The sex ratio is usually one to three males for every seven to nine females in a group. Mating occurs within the group. Named for their vocalizations, they may be heard most often around sunrise. This 'dawn chorus' sounds much more like roaring than howling, and it announces the howlers' position as a means to avoiding conflict with other groups. The call can be heard up to 5 km away. These monkeys commonly sleep or rest up to 70% of the day, making it one of the least active monkeys in the New World. Their habitat is forest, especially semideciduous and gallery.[2] Black howlers are folivorous, eating mostly leaves,[4] and occasionally fruit, such as figs. They generally prefer walking and climbing to running or leaping. The prehensile tail is very strong and acts as a fifth limb, allowing the monkeys greater versatility when climbing and allowing them greater safety in the occasional fall from a high branch. Because their limb structure makes terrestrial movement awkward, they spend most of their time in the trees and only come down for water during dry spells. Otherwise, the monkeys drink by wetting their hands on moist leaves, and then licking the water off their hands. Their lifespans are up to 20 years, but more commonly 15 years in the wild. In Argentina it is commonly kept as a pet due to its gentle nature.	</Info>
  </Monkey>

</ArrayOfMonkey>