<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	White-eared titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Whiteearedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The white-eared titi, Plecturocebus donacophilus, also known as the Bolivian titi or Bolivian gray titi, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from eastern Bolivia and an area of western Brazil. The species has a range that extends east from the Manique River in Beni Department, Bolivia to southern Rondônia in Brazil. The southern end of its range includes forests around the city of Santa Cruz de la Sierra. It is a medium-sized monkey with a grey back, orange underside and distinctive white ear tufts. It has an omnivorous diet, eating fruits, other plant materials and invertebrates. It is predated upon primarily by raptors, though felids and other monkey species have been known to attack the species. It is a monogamous species and lives in small groups of two to seven members consisting of the pair and their offspring. The family group has a home range of 0.5 to 14 hectares (1.2 to 34.6 acres) and the adults have a complex vocal repertoire to maintain their territory. It is also known for its characteristic twining of tails when groups are sitting together. White-eared titis can live for more than 25 years in captivity. The white-eared titi population has a declining trend. The decline is believed to be mainly caused by human-induced habitat loss and degradation. Despite this, the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) classified the species as being of least concern in 2008 as it has shown adaptability to habitat disturbance and is found over a wide range.The white-eared titi is a medium-sized primate with grey to orange pelage. The species does not exhibit sexual dimorphism; the male's head and body length averages 311 millimetres (12.2 in) while females average 340 millimetres (13 in). The white-eared titi's fluffy tail is longer than the length of its head and body together. It typically has thick fur, with a dorsal side and limbs that vary in colour from grey agouti to orange agouti, with an orange underside and white ear tufts. Body weight ranges from around 800 to 1,200 grams (1.8 to 2.6 lb), with the female generally a little lighter. The canine teeth are relatively short when compared with other New World monkeys. In captivity, the white-eared titi has been known to live for over 25 years.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Rio Beni titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>RioBenititi.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Rio Beni titi (Plecturocebus modestus) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Bolivia.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Rio Mayo titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>RioMayotiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Rio Mayo titi (Plecturocebus oenanthe) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Peru. The Rio Mayo titi, was thought previously to have a small range of origin in the Alto Mayo valley, but research has proven that the range extends southward and reaches the Huayamba River, as well as Bajo Mayo. It had been classified as vulnerable but due to major habitat loss and restricted living space, it is now classified as Critically Endangered. In October 2012, it was included in The World's 25 Most Endangered Primates list. An increase in deforestation is leading to the decrease in available living space for this titi monkey, forcing it to live in sympatry with another species of Callicebus. Yet in some areas, such drastic deforestation has resulted in extremely high population density. The Rio Mayo titi is better adapted to moderately populated areas, thus overpopulation negatively impacts the species.[6] The forests the Rio Mayo titi lives in are being destroyed for agricultural purposes, leaving little forest for the monkeys. They were only seen a few times and featured in museums until 2003 when more research was done on them. In order for this species to survive, their forests need to be protected to avoid overpopulation. Different conservation groups are working to help P. oenanthe survive. Neotropical Primate Conservation, Proyecto Mono Tocón and Amazónicos para la Amazonia are working in the more southern areas to protect the monkey. The Rio Mayo titi is a fairly inconspicuous creature, making observation and research difficult to obtain. Therefore, the traditional use of transect observation to monitor the monkey's population, is less effective. Instead, other methods of calculating the titi monkey's density in certain areas have been taken, such as research into the species-specific calls endemic to a certain area. The appearance of the Rio Mayo titi varies based on their location. In one part of Ecuador, the titis were seen to have reddish brown fur on their back, limbs and chest and lighter reddish brown fur in the on the outside of their limbs. They had a dark brown-red forehead, sideburns and beard and small white tufts of fur coming out of their ears. They had a light colored throat, black hands, tail and nails and cream colored underparts with white hairs on their muzzle. Their fur was short and spikey. In another part of Ecuador, the titis had a light red fur on their forehead, sideburns and beard, quite a lot of fur by their ears, dark hands with white fur on them, red underparts and chest, a gray tail and whitish hair above their nose, eyebrows and muzzle. Their fur was frizzy.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Ollala brothers's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Ollalabrothersstiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Ollala brothers's titi (Plecturocebus olallae) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Bolivia.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	White-coated titi	</Name>
    <Location>	 Bolivia, Brazil, and Paraguay.	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Whitecoatedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The white-coated titi (Plecturocebus pallescens) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in Bolivia, Brazil, and Paraguay.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Baptista Lake titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>BaptistaLaketiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Baptista Lake titi, Plecturocebus baptista, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was originally described as Callicebus baptista in 1939.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Prince Bernhard's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>PrinceBernhardstiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Prince Bernhard's titi (Plecturocebus bernhardi) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was formally described in 2002 by Marc van Roosmalen and Russell Mittermeier, and named after Prince Bernard of the Netherlands. Locals were shown a photograph of the monkey and asked if they knew of its whereabouts, it was referred to as a 'Zog-Zog'. This titi has dark orange sideburns and chest, a reddish-brown back, and a black tail with a white tip. It is about 94 centimeters (37 in) in length, although 56 centimeters (22 in) is taken up by its tail.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Brown titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Peru, and Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Browntiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The brown titi, Plecturocebus brunneus, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in Brazil, Peru, and Bolivia. It was originally described as Callicebus brunneus in 1842.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Ashy black titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Ashyblacktiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The ashy black titi, Plecturocebus cinerascens, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was originally described as Callicebus cinerascens in 1823.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Hoffmanns's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Hoffmannsstiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Hoffmanns's titi (Plecturocebus hoffmannsi) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was described as Callicebus hoffmannsi in 1908.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Red-bellied titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Redbelliedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The red-bellied titi or dusky titi (Plecturocebus moloch) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It lives in forests and thickets. It has a rounded head and a thick, soft coat and frequently adopts a characteristic posture with the body hunched, limbs close together, and a tail hanging down. The body is 28–39 cm long, and the tail is 33–49 cm. It can move quite fast if necessary but rarely does so and generally stays within a fairly small area, feeding on fruit, insects, spiders, small birds, and bird's eggs. It is diurnal and moves in pairs or family groups, which communicate by means of a wide repertoire of sounds. The female gives birth to a single offspring. The red-bellied titi has an average head and body length of 333 mm (13.1 in) for males and 331 mm (13.0 in) for females, showing no sexual dimorphism. Its tail has a greater length than the head and body combined.[4] Males weigh between 850–1,200 g (1.87–2.65 lb) while females range from 700–1,020 g (1.54–2.25 lb). It has a larger pollex than its hallux. It has six palmar pads and nails on each of its five digits. It has a dental formula of i 2/2, p 3/3, m 3/3 with a total of 36. Its upper incisors are elongated and the incisiform canines barely extend beyond the other teeth. The upper molars are sometimes tricuspid and the lower premolars are relatively simple. Upper and lower molars are quadricuspid. It has relatively large ears often obscured by the fur on side of the head. The nose has a wide internal septum and the nares open laterally. In adults, the pelage of the back can be grey, reddish, or brown. It usually has white or black bands on its forehead. This color pattern found both in young and adults. The ear has a helical margin that is pulled upward and towards the back. The anterior superior margins are rolled. Tragus and antitragus are small, lobulated and equal in size. The manus has a unique raided pads; the interdigital pads are separated from the palm by a structure called deep flex urge line. The palm consist of two elongated central pads, a hypothenar pad and a thenar pad. The skull is orthognathous, orbits are unfenestrated, balls are inflated ventrally, and a large sinus found above the nasal. The foramen magnum is located towards the front, and the atlas has shallow anterior articular facets which allow the condyles to attach. Anterior margin of the lacrimal fossa is formed by or near the maxilla. The premaxilla is short, giving the appearance of a small, not especially prognathic face relative to other platyrrhines. The corpus of the mandible deepens posteriorly and the ramus is tall. The hyoid bone is expanded and highly convex ventrally.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Barbara Brown's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>BarbaraBrownstiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Barbara Brown's titi (Callicebus barbarabrownae), also popularly known as the blond titi monkey or northern Bahian blond titi, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey. This critically endangered species is endemic to the Caatinga in northeastern Brazil, and it is estimated that less than 250 mature individuals remain. The blonde titi monkey is listed as Critically Endangered due to small population size. The blond titi monkey is endemic to the Atlantic forests of eastern Brazil, where it is found in the coastal highlands of Bahia and Sergipe States. Most of their population is found between the Paraguaçu River (north) and Salvador (south), and west towards Mirorós. The estimated population is 260 individuals and is decreasing.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Coimbra Filho's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>CoimbraFilhostiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Coimbra Filho's titi (Callicebus coimbrai) or just Coimbra's titi is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to forests in the Brazilian states of Bahia and Sergipe. It was first discovered by Shuji Kobayashi. It is considered one of the most endangered of all Neotropical primates. It is named after Adelmar F. Coimbra-Filho, founder and Former Director of the Rio de Janeiro Primate Centre, in honor of his work in the field of Brazilian primatology and biology. The most distinct of Coimbra Filho's titi's features, from other members of the personatus group, include its black forehead, crown, and ear area, as well as a zebra-like pattern on the anterior of its back. Coimbra Filho's titi is also differentiated from other members of the personatus group by the shape of both its skull and its teeth. Compared to other members of its group, the skull is smaller, and shaped slightly differently. Its teeth are also more U-shaped, as opposed to the more V-shaped teeth exhibited by other members of the personatus group. It also features different dental topography on its upper first and second molars when compared to other members of the group.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Coastal black-handed titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Coastalblackhandedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The coastal black-handed titi (Callicebus melanochir) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black-fronted titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackfrontedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black-fronted titi (Callicebus nigrifrons) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Atlantic titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Atlantictiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Atlantic titi or masked titi (Callicebus personatus) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. The Atlantic titi is part of the genus Callicebus which is composed of thirteen species and sixteen subspecies. Some more recent classifications of titis recognise many more species, and split the genus into three separate genera. The C. personatus group is retained in Callicebus. Three subspecies of Callicebus personatus have been described in scientific literature: C.p. melanochir, C.p. nigrifrons, and C.p. personatus, each of which has been treated as a full species by some authors. Atlantic titis are territorial, middle-sized, cebid monkeys; usually 1–2 kg in size. C. personatus are found primarily in the humid forests east of the Andes Mountains, specifically in the coastal, inland forests of south-eastern Brazil. The states they have been documented to dwell within include Bahia, Espírito Santo, Minas Gerais, Rio de Janeiro, and São Paulo. Of all the Callicebus species, Atlantic titi monkeys have the largest geographic range except for C. torquatus, covering approximately 1,000 kilometers. They customarily share their living area with other monkeys such as the lion tamarin and spider monkey.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Chestnut-bellied titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Chestnutbelliedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The chestnut-bellied titi (Plecturocebus caligatus) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was originally described as Callicebus caligatus in 1842.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Coppery titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Peru, and Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Copperytiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The coppery titi (Plecturocebus cupreus) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in the Amazon of Brazil and Peru, and perhaps northern Bolivia. It was described as Callicebus cupreus in 1823.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	White-tailed titi	</Name>
    <Location>	 Colombia, Ecuador and Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Whitetailedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The white-tailed titi, Plecturocebus discolor, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in Colombia, Ecuador and Peru. It was described in 1848 as Callicebus discolor.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Ornate titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Ornatetiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The ornate titi (Plecturocebus ornatus) is a species of titi and is the smallest member of the family Pitheciidae, which also includes uakaris and saki monkeys. As it is a member of this family, it is classified as a type of New World monkey. It is endemic to eastern Colombia, and the only member of the Plecturocebus moloch group to occur north of the Rios Amazonas/Solimes/Napo axis, living at least 350 km away from the closest other member, the white-tailed titi (Plecturocebus discolor), which lives in the south of Colombia. It was once classified as the same species as the white-tailed titi, but is now officially recognized as its own species. The ornate titi is also terrestrial. The ornate titi is present on the IUCN Red List of endangered species, being recognized as “Vulnerable”, and having a general decrease in population trends. The ornate titi has a thick, dense, fluffy, coat, with white ears and forehead, and grey hands and feet. The rest of the body is a bright chestnut red, apart from the tail, which is a dark-reddish brown or black, becoming white at the tip, and, similar to most titi species, is longer than its body. Male and female ornate titis do not differentiate significantly in appearance, however, generally, females tend to be larger, with an average male body length of 633 mm, and an average female body length of 752 mm.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Stephen Nash's titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>StephenNashstiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Stephen Nash's titi (Plecturocebus stephennashi), also known as just Nash's titi or Stephen Nash's monkey, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to the eastern bank of the Purus River in Brazil. It was discovered by Marc van Roosmalen in 2001 when local fishermen brought specimens to his breeding center. It was described in 2002. It was named in honor of Stephen D. Nash, an illustrator for Conservation International, the organization that funded van Roosmalen's work.The monkey is largely silver with a black forehead and red sideburns and chest, as well as on the underside of the species' limbs. It is 28 inches long, although 17 inches is taken up by the titi's tail.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Lucifer titi	</Name>
    <Location>	 Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Lucifertiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Lucifer titi (Cheracebus lucifer) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru. It was described as Callicebus lucifer in 1914. The Lucifer titi has previously been treated as part of C. torquatus, the collared titi.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black titi	</Name>
    <Location>	 Brazil, Colombia, and Venezuela	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blacktiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black titi, Cheracebus lugens, is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. It is found in Brazil, Colombia, and Venezuela. It was described in 1811 as Calicebus lugens.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Red-headed titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Redheadedtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The red-headed titi (Cheracebus regulus) is a species of titi, a type of New World monkey, endemic to Brazil. It was originally described as Callicebus regulus in 1927.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Collared titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Collaredtiti.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The collared titi (Cheracebus torquatus) is a species or a closely related complex of species of titi, a type of New World monkey, from South America. Five adults weighed an average of 1462 g (range 1410–1722 g) with a head-body length of around 290–390 mm and a tail length of about 350–400 mm.[4] The face has very little hair, being limited to sparse short white hairs over a black skin. There is no sexual dimorphism, although the male has canines a bit longer than the female. The species has the smallest karyotype known for primates, 2n=16 recently described by Bonvicino et al. The pelage is typically uniformly reddish brown or blackish brown. The tail is blackish mixed with some reddish hairs with hands and feet whitish or dark brown. This pelage contrasts in all of the subspecies with a band of white hair which extends upward from the chest and follows the neck, prolonging itself to the ears. This extension to the ears is weak in Callicebus torquatus torquatus, a subspecies not confirmed for Colombia and different from the other subspecies which have white extending to the base of the ears.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Madidi titi	</Name>
    <Location>	Bolivia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Madidititi.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Madidi titi, also known as the GoldenPalace.com monkey or the golden palace monkey, is a titi, a kind of New World monkey, discovered in western Bolivia's Madidi National Park in 2004. Its scientific name is Plecturocebus aureipalatii, the specific epithet meaning 'of the Golden Palace', in reference to GoldenPalace.com, an online casino which paid US$650,000 to have the species named after them, with benefits going toward the nonprofit organization that maintains the park where the titi was discovered. The species was discovered in low-lying lands of northwestern Bolivia, in the forest at the foot of the Andes. Studies indicate that it inhabits the western bank of the river Beni. The extension to the east and north of its range is not known. Preliminary studies indicate that the species is not endemic to Bolivia, with habitats that may extend to the south of Peru (at least to the Tambopata River).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
</ArrayOfMonkey>