<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Colombian white-faced capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Panama, Coloumbia, Ecuador	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Colombianwhitefacedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Colombian white-faced capuchin (Cebus capucinus), also known as the Colombian white-headed capuchin or Colombian white-throated capuchin, is a medium-sized New World monkey of the family Cebidae, subfamily Cebinae. It is native to the extreme eastern portion of Panama and the extreme north-western portion of South America in western Colombia and northwestern Ecuador. The Colombian white-faced capuchin was one of the many species originally described by Linnaeus in his 18th century work, Systema Naturae. It is a member of the family Cebidae, the family of New World monkeys containing capuchin monkeys and squirrel monkeys. It is the type species for the genus Cebus, the genus that includes all the capuchin monkeys. Until the 21st century the Panamanian white-faced capuchin, Cebus imitator, was considered conspecific with the Colombian white-faced capuchin, as the subspecies C. capucinus imitator. Some primatologists continue to consider the Panamanian and Colombian white-faced capuchins as a single species. In 2012 a study by Boubli, et al demonstrated that C. imitator and C. capucinus split up to 2 million years ago. Although the Panamanian white-faced capuchin is the most well-studied capuchin monkey species, as of 2014 there had been no field studies of the Colombian white-faced capuchin. Two subspecies of Colombian white-faced capuchin are recognized: C. c. capucinus, from mainland South America and Panama and C. c. curtus, from the Pacific island of Gorgona, sometimes referred to as the Gorgona white-faced capuchin. Like other monkeys in the genus Cebus, the Panamanian white-faced capuchin is named after the order of Capuchin friars because the cowls of these friars closely resemble the monkey's head coloration.[9][10] The coloration is black on the body, tail, legs and the top of the head, with white chest, throat, face, shoulders and upper arms. The head and body length is between 33 and 45 cm (13 and 18 in) with a tail length of between 35 and 55 mm (1.4 and 2.2 in). Males weigh between 3 and 4 kg (6.6 and 8.8 lb), while females are about 27% smaller, weighing between 1.5 and 3 kg (3.3 and 6.6 lb). C. c. curtus has a shorter tail. The white-faced capuchin is found in the extreme north-western strip between the Pacific Ocean and the Andes Mountains in Colombia and northwestern Ecuador. C. c. capucinus has been listed as least concern from a conservation standpoint by the IUCN, while C. c. curtus has been listed as vulnerable.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Panamanian white-faced capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Central America	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Panamanianwhitefacedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Panamanian white-faced capuchin (Cebus imitator), also known as the Panamanian white-headed capuchin or Central American white-faced capuchin, is a medium-sized New World monkey of the family Cebidae, subfamily Cebinae. Native to the forests of Central America, the white-faced capuchin is important to rainforest ecology for its role in dispersing seeds and pollen. Among the best known monkeys, the Panamanian white-faced capuchin is recognized as the typical companion to the organ grinder. In recent years the species has become popular in North American media, particularly in the Pirates of the Caribbean film series. It is a highly intelligent monkey and has been trained to assist paraplegic persons. It is a medium-sized monkey, weighing up to 3.9 kg (8.6 lb). It is mostly black, but with a pink face and white on much of the front part of the body, giving it its common name. It has a distinctive prehensile tail that is often carried coiled up and is used to help support the monkey when it is feeding beneath a branch.In the wild, the Panamanian white-faced capuchin is versatile, living in many different types of forest, and eating many different types of food, including fruit, other plant material, invertebrates, and small vertebrates. It lives in troops that can exceed 20 animals and include both males and females. It is noted for its tool use, including rubbing plants over its body in an apparent use of herbal medicine, and also using tools as weapons and for getting to food. It is a long-lived monkey, with a maximum recorded age of over 54 years.Panamanian white-faced capuchins are highly social, living in groups of 16 individuals on average, about three quarters of which are females. Groups consists of related females, immigrant males, and offspring. On average, females birth offspring every 27 months even though they mate throughout the year. Females tend to stay within their original group while males leave their natal group when they are 4 years old and change groups every 4 years after. Both male and female capuchins exhibit different dominance behaviors within the group.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	 Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Peru and Venezuela.	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Humboldtswhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin (Cebus albifrons) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey. The species name Cebus albifrons was formerly considered to also include several types of white-fronted capuchin monkey which are now regarded as separate species based on genetic studies by Boubli and Lynch Alfaro. The head and body length of Humboldt's white-fronted capuchins is about 37.5 cm (14.8 in).[4][5] Tail length for males is about 42.5 cm (16.7 in) and it is between 41 and 46 cm (16 and 18 in) for females. Males weigh about 2.40 kg (5.3 lb) and females weigh about 2.23 kg (4.9 lb). They have grayish brown fur on the back with darker limbs and yellowish brown hands and feet. The front is cream colored. Their face is pink and they have a dark brown wedge-shaped cap which is clearly separated from the lighter forehead.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Ecuadorian capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Peru, Ecuador	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Ecuadoriancapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Ecuadorian capuchin (Cebus aequatorialis), or Ecuadorian white-fronted capuchin is a species of gracile capuchin monkey of the family Cebidae. It was formerly classified as a subspecies of the white-fronted capuchin. Mittermeier and Rylands elevated it to a separate species in 2013. It lives in tropical forests in Ecuador and Peru. It is listed as critically endangered.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Marañón white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Maranonwhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Marañón white-fronted capuchin or Peruvian white-fronted capuchin (Cebus yuracus) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from the upper Amazon Basin. It had been regarded as synonymous with the shock-headed capuchin (C. cuscinus), which was then considered a subspecies of Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin, but it was classified as a separate species by Mittermeier and Rylands based on genetic studies by Boubli. Marañón white-fronted capuchin in Lago Pilchicocha, Napo Valley, Ecuador. The Marañón white-fronted capuchin lives in wet forests of the upper Amazon basin in southern Colombia, eastern Ecuador, northeastern Peru and likely eastern Brazil. Males have a head and body length of about 43 cm (17 in) with a tail length of about 47 cm (19 in). Females have a head and body length about 37 cm (15 in) with a tail length of about 45 cm (18 in).Marañón white-fronted capuchins sometimes formed mixed groups with the Ecuadorian squirrel monkey.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Río Cesar white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>RioCesarwhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Río Cesar white-fronted capuchin (Cebus cesarae) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from the Río Cesar Valley in northern Colombia. It had previously been considered a subspecies of the white-fronted capuchin (C. albifrons). Genetic analysis by Jean Boubli in 2012 revealed that the Río Cesar white-fronted capuchin is actually more closely related to the Colombian white-faced capuchin (C. capucinus) than it is to C. albifrons. Some authors regard it to be a subspecies of the varied white-fronted capuchin (C. versicolor cesarae). The Río Cesar white-fronted capuchin lives in dry semi-deciduous forest, gallery forest and mangroves. Its fur is light colored. Males have a head and body length between 30.8 and 40.7 cm (12.1 and 16.0 in) with a tail length of between 41.9 and 49.5 cm (16.5 and 19.5 in). Females have a head and body length between 35.3 and 38.5 cm (13.9 and 15.2 in) with a tail length of between 46.1 and 50 cm (18.1 and 19.7 in).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Santa Marta white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>SantaMartawhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Santa Marta white-fronted capuchin (Cebus malitiosus) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from Colombia. It was formerly considered a subspecies of the Cebus albifrons or a synonym of the Colombian white-faced capuchin (C. capucinus), but Mittermeier and Rylands elevated it to a species in 2013, following previous work by Rylands, Hershkovitz, Cooper and Hernandez-Camacho. The IUCN follows this taxonomy. The Santa Marta white-fronted capuchin range is restricted to forests near the northwest base of Sierra de Santa Marta in northern Colombia. Males have a head and body about 45.7 cm (18.0 in) long and a tail about 43.3 cm (17.0 in) long.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Shock-headed capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Bolivia, Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Shockheadedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The shock-headed capuchin (Cebus cuscinus) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from Bolivia and Peru. It was previously classified as a subspecies of the Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin (C. albifrons), but in 2013 Mittermeier and Rylands elevated it to a separate species, following genetic studies by Boubli et al in 2012 and Lynch Alfaro et al in 2010. The shock-headed capuchin lives in lowland and seasonally inundated forests of the upper Amazon Basin, as well as montane forests of the western Andes Mountains up to elevations of 1,800 m (5,900 ft). Males have a head and body length of about 40 cm (16 in) with a tail length of about 44 cm (17 in). Females have a head and body length between 39 and 46 cm (15 and 18 in) with a tail length between 39 and 47.5 cm (15.4 and 18.7 in).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Sierra de Perijá white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia, Venezuela	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>SierradePerijawhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Sierra de Perijá white-fronted capuchin (Cebus leucocephalus) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from Colombia and Venezuela. It had formerly been regarded as a subspecies of the Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin but was reclassified by Mittermeier and Rylands as a separate species in 2013, based on genetic studies by Jean Boubli. The range of the Sierra de Perijá white-fronted capuchin is restricted to the forests in a portion of northern Colombia and northwest Venezuela. Males have a head and body that ranges between 37 and 40.7 cm (14.6 and 16.0 in) with a tail length of between 39.2 and 49.9 mm (1.54 and 1.96 in).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Spix's white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Spixswhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Spix's white-fronted capuchin (Cebus unicolor) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey. It had previously been classified as a subspecies of the Humboldt's white-fronted capuchin (C. albifrons). Following genetic studies by Boubli, et al, Mittermeier and Ryland elevated it to a full species. Spix's white-fronted capuchin has a wide range within the upper Amazon Basin in Brazil and Peru.[1] It also occurs in northern Bolivia.  It has a head and body length between 36.5 and 37.5 cm (14.4 and 14.8 in) and a tail length of between 42 and 46 cm (17 and 18 in).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Varied white-fronted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Colombia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Variedwhitefrontedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The varied white-fronted capuchin (Cebus versicolor) is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from Colombia. It had been classified as a subspecies of the white-fronted capuchin (C. albifrons) Genetic analysis by Jean Boubli in 2012 revealed it to be a separate species. Some authors regard the Río Cesar white-fronted capuchin to be a subspecies of the varied white-fronted capuchin. The varied white-fronted capuchin lives in lowland moist forest and in palm swamps in the Río Magdalena Valley of northern Colombia. It has reddish fur on its back, forearms and the front of its legs, contrasting with lighter fur overall. It has a dark brown crown on its head contrasting with light fur on the temples, forehead, chin, throat and on the sides of its face and neck. It has a head and body length between 45 and 50.5 cm (17.7 and 19.9 in) with a tail length of between 42 and 45.5 mm (1.65 and 1.79 in).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Wedge-capped capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	 Brazil, Guyana, French Guiana, Suriname, Venezuela 	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Wedgecappedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The wedge-capped capuchin or weeper capuchin (Cebus olivaceus) is a capuchin monkey from South America. It is found in northern Brazil, Guyana, French Guiana, Suriname, Venezuela and possibly northern Colombia. The genus Cebus is divided into several different species. However, taxonomists argue over the specific divisions within the genus, which are uncertain and controversial. Cebus olivaceus is known to dwell in tall, primary forest and travel over long distances during the day. These primates are medium-sized monkeys with distinctive "wedge cap" markings on their head and slightly longer limbs than other capuchins for jumping through the forest canopy. Similar to other capuchin monkeys, the diet of wedge-capped capuchin primarily consists of fruits, invertebrates, other plant parts, and on rare occasions small vertebrates. They have also been known to rub millipedes against their fur, especially in the rainy seasons, as a potential means of mosquito repellent. Although this species is classified as an animal of least concern by IUCN Red List of Threatened Species, it falls prey to many predators in South America ranging from vultures to jaguars. Cebus olivaceus is a polygamous species that lives in groups anywhere from 5-30 individuals, with a female biased sex ratios. The group is organized according to a pre-determined hierarchal system of dominance for both males and females. Although biological lineage is less of a factor of dominance for males than it is for females, due to male migration between groups. Wedge-capped capuchin partake in several behavioral mechanisms to assert and maintain dominance within the group including: infanticide, when an infant is deliberately killed; grooming, used to facilitate social rapport; and alloparenting, which is when members of the group care for offspring that are not their own.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Brown weeper capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Venezuela	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Brownweepercapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Brown weeper capuchin (Cebus brunneus) or Venezuelan brown capuchin is a species of gracile capuchin monkey from Venezuela. It had previously been considered to be synonymous with the Guianan weeper capuchin (C. olivaceus) but genetic analysis by Jean Boubli revealed it to be a separate species. Following Boubli, Mittermeier and Rylands recognized the Trinidad white-fronted capuchin to be synonymous with the brown weeper capuchin, but other authors such as the IUCN regard that as a separate species C. trinitatis. The brown weeper capuchin has brown, thick fur with a dark wedge on the forehead and lighter face, cheeks and chin. Its head and body are about 42 centimetres (17 in) with a 44 cm (17 in) tail. It lives in various types of forest in the Cordillera de la Costa in northern Venezuela, in dry semi-deciduous forests and gallery forests in the Western Venezuelan Llanos, as well as in Trinidad (under the assumption that the Trinidad white-fronted capuchin is synonymous). Trinidad white-fronted capuchins have been observed using leaves as cups to drink water from tree cavities. The leaves used were modified before by changing the shape of the leaf. The leaves are discarded after one use, meaning that a different leaf is used for repeat visits. These observations suggest that, like the common chimpanzee, wild capuchins demonstrate tool manufacture and use in foraging-related contexts.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Kaapori capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Kaaporicapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Kaapori capuchin (Cebus kaapori) is a capuchin monkey endemic to Brazil. This species is located the Brazilian states of Pará and Maranhão along the Atlantic coast to the north of the country, and usually found in dense forest regions, where their food is more abundant, but can also be found in secondary growth areas during the dry season. Like most Capuchins, the Kaapori capuchin is diurnal, arboreal and omnivorous, their diet consisting of small animals and plants. They eat roughly equal portions of plants and animals, mainly feeding on ripe fruits and small insects and invertebrates such as spiders, snails, wasps, caterpillars, grasshoppers, ants, and bird eggs. It weighs about 2 – 3 kg. The Kaapori capuchin is polygamous, and females usually give birth to one infant per birth, with twins being rare. Births usually occur every 2 years, but they may occur closer together if a baby dies, with a gestation period of 150 – 180 days. Formerly considered a subspecies of the wedge-capped capuchin (Cebus olivaceus), it was recently elevated to species status.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tufted capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	South America	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Tuftedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The tufted capuchin (Sapajus apella), also known as brown capuchin, black-capped capuchin, or pin monkey is a New World primate from South America. As traditionally defined, it is one of the most widespread primates in the Neotropics, but it has recently been recommended considering the black-striped, black and golden-bellied capuchins as separate species in a new genus, thereby effectively limiting the tufted capuchin to the Amazon basin and nearby regions. The tufted capuchin is an omnivorous animal, mostly feeding on fruits and invertebrates, although it sometimes feeds on small vertebrates (e.g. lizards and bird chicks) and other plant parts. It can be found in many different kinds of environment, including moist tropical and subtropical forest, dry forest, and disturbed or secondary forest. Like other capuchins, it is a social animal, forming groups of 8 to 15 individuals that are led by an alpha or dominant male. The tufted capuchin is more powerfully built than the other capuchins, with rougher fur and a long, thick tail. It has a bundle of long, hardened hair on the forehead that can be raised as a sort of 'wig'. The fur is brownish gray, with the belly being somewhat lighter-colored than the rest of the body. The hands and feet are black. The tail is prehensile: strong and can be used for grasping, as an extra limb. The tufted capuchin has a head-body length of 32 to 57 centimetres (13 to 22 in), a tail length of 38 to 56 centimetres (15 to 22 in), and a weight of 1.9 to 4.8 kilograms (4.2 to 10.6 lb), with the males generally being larger and heavier than the females.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black-striped capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackstripedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black-striped capuchin (Sapajus libidinosus), also known as the bearded capuchin, is a capuchin monkey from South America. It was the first non-ape primate in which tool usage was documented in the wild, as individuals have been seen cracking nuts by placing them on a stone 'anvil' while hitting them with another large stone. Adaptations to carrying large stones and fruit include strengthened back and leg muscles that permit the monkey to walk on its hind legs while carrying stones. The black-striped capuchin has traditionally been considered a subspecies of the tufted capuchin. On the contrary, the southern population here included in S. libidinosus has sometimes been considered another species, Azaras's capuchin (S. cay) (syn. S. paraguayanus). The black-striped capuchin is found in the Caatinga, Cerrado, and Pantanal of Brazil. Some confusion surrounds the taxon juruanus, here included as a subspecies of the black-striped capuchin. It has been considered to occur from the upper Juruá River east and south to Mato Grosso, or alternatively entirely restricted to the region near the upper Juruá River. In the latter case, its range would be surrounded by C. apella, leading to doubts over its true taxonomic status.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Argentina	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black capuchin, (Sapajus nigritus), also known as the black-horned capuchin, is a capuchin monkey from the Atlantic Forest in south-eastern Brazil and far north-eastern Argentina. Historically, it was included as a subspecies of the tufted capuchin. The black capuchin is a social animal. It likes to live in groups, usually consisting of 6 to 20 members, and is hierarchal. Despite the fact that these groups tend to be made up of more females than males, the alpha female of the group is submissive to the alpha male. Communication within groups consists of bodily, facial and vocal communications. One example of this is the 'scream embrace mechanism’, a high pitched called used to regroup (usually male) members of a group.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Golden-bellied capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Goldenbelliedcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The golden-bellied capuchin (Sapajus xanthosternos), also known as the yellow-breasted or buffy-headed capuchin, is a species of New World monkey. Although there are differences between individuals as well as between the sexes and across age groups, S. xanthosternos is described as having a distinctive yellow to golden red chest, belly and upper arms. Its face is a light brown and its cap for which the capuchins were first named is a dark brown/black or light brown. Formerly thought to be a subspecies of tufted capuchin (S. apella), it was elevated to the status of species. Despite this previous classification, S. xanthosternos does not have very evident tufts, as they are oriented towards the rear of the skull and are hardly noticeable. A band of short hair around the upper part of the face with speckled colouring contrasts with the darker surrounding areas. The limbs and tail are also darkly coloured. Populations of S. xanthosternos are restricted to the Atlantic forest of south-eastern Bahia, Brazil, due possibly to high degrees of interference from humans. Historically they probably would have inhabited the entire area east of, and north to, the Rio São Francisco. The largest continuous area of forest in its known range, the Una Biological Reserve in Bahia, is estimated to contain a population of 185 individuals. As of 2004, there were 85 individuals in zoos and breeding facilities in Europe and Brazil	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Blond capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blondcapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The blond capuchin (Sapajus flavius) is a species of the capuchin monkeys group, the genus Sapajus. This critically endangered species was rediscovered in 2006. It is endemic to northeastern Brazil, and only an estimated 180 individuals remain. The blond capuchin was first described as "caitaia" by Georg Marcgrave in 1648. In 1774 Johann Christian Daniel von Schreber posited Simia flavia as an independent species, but it had long lacked any specimen. It was not until in 2006 when researchers made its neotype designation. In their neotype designation article, de Oliveira and Langguth confirmed the consistency of Marcgrave’s, Schreber’s, and their capuchins, attributed the authority to Schreber, and established a new combination of its scientific name, C. flavius Schreber, 1774. In the same year, 2006, Mendes Pontes and Malta reported C. queirozi as a new species. However, de Oliveira and his collaborators pointed out the existence of the previous studies, that is, those of Marcgrave and Schreber, as well as the inadequacy of Mendes Pontes and Malta's designation of the type specimen, and therefore considered C. queirozi to be a junior synonym. Rylands and Mittermeier followed de Oliveira and Langguth’s view. In 2011, Jessica Lynch Alfaro et al. proposed that the robust capuchins such (formerly the C. apella group) be placed in a separate genus, Sapajus, from the gracile capuchins (formerly the C. capucinus group) which retain the genus Cebus. Pelage uniformly golden; whitish cap on the head; face pinkish; palms of the hands and feet black. Head and body about 35–40 cm; tail nearly equivalent. Weight about 2–3 kg.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Azaras's capuchin	</Name>
    <Location>	Paraguay, bolivia, argentina, brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Azarasscapuchin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Azaras's capuchin or hooded capuchin (Sapajus cay) is a species of robust capuchin. It occurs in eastern Paraguay, southeastern Bolivia, northern Argentina, and Brazil, at Mato Grosso do Sul and Mato Grosso states, in Pantanal.Its habitat consists of subtropical, humid, semi-deciduous, gallery forests and forested regions of the pantanals. Formerly, it was considered a subspecies of black-striped capuchin, according to Groves (2005) with the name Cebus libidinosus paraguayanus, but Silva Jr. (2001) considered it a separated species. They are considered as frugivores-insectivores which means that their diet mainly consists of a variety of fruits, seeds, arthropods, frogs, small mammals, etc.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Central American squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Paraguay, Costa Rica	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>CentralAmericansquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Azaras's capuchin or hooded capuchin (Sapajus cay) is a species of robust capuchin. It occurs in eastern Paraguay, southeastern Bolivia, northern Argentina, and Brazil, at Mato Grosso do Sul and Mato Grosso states, in Pantanal.Its habitat consists of subtropical, humid, semi-deciduous, gallery forests and forested regions of the pantanals. Formerly, it was considered a subspecies of black-striped capuchin, according to Groves (2005) with the name Cebus libidinosus paraguayanus, but Silva Jr. (2001) considered it a separated species. They are considered as frugivores-insectivores which means that their diet mainly consists of a variety of fruits, seeds, arthropods, frogs, small mammals, etc.The Central American squirrel monkey or (Saimiri oerstedii), also known as red-backed squirrel monkey, is a squirrel monkey species from the Pacific coast of Costa Rica and Panama. It is restricted to the northwestern tip of Panama near the border with Costa Rica, and the central and southern Pacific coast of Costa Rica, primarily in Manuel Antonio and Corcovado National Parks. It is a small monkey with an orange back and a distinctive white and black facial mask. It has an omnivorous diet, eating fruits, other plant materials, invertebrates and some small vertebrates. In turn, it has a number of predators, including raptors, cats and snakes. It lives in large groups that typically contain between 20 and 75 monkeys. It has one of the most egalitarian social structures of all monkeys. Females do not form dominance hierarchies, and males do so only at breeding season. Females become sexually mature at 2½ years, and males at 4 to 5 years. Sexually mature females leave the natal group, but males can remain with their natal group their entire life. The Central American squirrel monkey can live for more than 15 years. The Central American squirrel monkey population declined precipitously after the 1970s. This decline is believed to be caused by deforestation, hunting, and capture to be kept as pets. Efforts are underway to preserve the species. Despite the threats to the population, in 2008 the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) upgraded its conservation status from "endangered" to "vulnerable".The Central American squirrel monkey differs in coloration from South American squirrel monkeys. While South American squirrel monkeys tend to be primarily greenish in color, the Central American species has an orange back with olive shoulders, hips and tail and white undersides. The hands and feet are also orange. There is a black cap at the top of the head, and a black tip at the end of the tail. Males generally have lighter caps than females. The face is white with black rims around the eyes and black around the nose and mouth. The two subspecies are similar in coloration, but differ in the shade of the cap. The northern subspecies, living in Central Pacific Costa Rica, has a lighter cap than the southern subspecies, which lives in Panama and in parts of Costa Rica near Panama. The southern subspecies also has more yellowish limbs and underparts. Adults reach a length of between 266 and 291 millimetres (10.5 and 11.5 in), excluding tail, and a weight between 600 and 950 grams (21 and 34 oz).[5][9] The tail is longer than the body, and between 362 and 389 mm (14.3 and 15.3 in) in length. As with other squirrel monkeys, there is considerable sexual dimorphism. On average, males weigh 16% more than females. Males have an average body weight of 829 g (29.2 oz) and females average 695 g (24.5 oz). Squirrel monkeys have the largest brains of all primates relative to their body size; the Central American squirrel monkey's brain weighs about 25.7 g (0.91 oz), or about 4% of its body weight. Unlike larger relatives, such as the capuchin, spider and howler monkeys, Central American squirrel monkeys do not have a fully prehensile tail, except as newborn infants, and the tail is primarily used to help with balance	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Guianan squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Guiana, Venezuela and Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Guianansquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Guianan squirrel monkey (Saimiri sciureus) is a species of squirrel monkey from Guiana, Venezuela and Brazil. S. scuireus formerly applied to Humboldt's squirrel monkey and Collins' squirrel monkey, but genetic research in 2009 and 2015 revealed that these are distinct species. Guianan squirrel monkey males have a body between 25 and 37 centimetres (9.8 and 14.6 in) long with a tail between 36 and 40 centimetres (14 and 16 in) long. Females have a body between 25 and 34 centimetres (9.8 and 13.4 in) long with a tail between 36 and 47 centimetres (14 and 19 in) long. Males weigh between 550 and 1,400 grams (19 and 49 oz) and females weigh between 550 and 1,200 grams (19 and 42 oz). The Guianan squirrel monkey has a pink face, black muzzle and white arches over the eyes. The crown of its head is olive or olive gray. The fur on its back can vary in color among gray, olive or orange, but the belly is white and the arms are yellow-orange.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Humboldt's squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Venezuela	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Humboldtssquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Humboldt's squirrel monkey (Saimiri cassiquiarensis) is a species of squirrel monkey from Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Venezuela. It had previously been considered a subspecies of the common squirrel monkey, S. scuireus, but was elevated to full species status based on a genetic study by Carretero-Pinzón in 2009. A genetic study by Jessica Lynch Alfaro, et al indicated that the Ecuadorian squirrel monkey may be synonymous with Saimiri cassiquiarensis. As of 2018, the Ecuadorian squirrel monkey is generally regarded as a subspecies of Humboldt's squirrel monkey, S. cassiquiarensis macrodon. Humboldt's squirrel monkey have a head and body length of between 25 and 37 cm (9.8 and 14.6 in) with a tail between 36 and 45 cm (14 and 18 in). Its coloration is similar to that of the Guianan squirrel monkey but the fur on the base of the crown is golden yellow as compared with gray for the Guianan squirrel monkey. It eats fruits when available, primarily between January and June, and also eats insects.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Collins' squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Collinssquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	Collins' squirrel monkey (Saimiri collinsii) is a species of squirrel monkey from Brazil. It had been considered a subspecies of the common squirrel monkey (S. sciureus) until a genetic study by Jessica Lynch Alfaro et al. elevated it to species status. Male Collins' squirrel monkeys have a head and body length of about 38 cm (15 in) with a 37.6 cm (14.8 in) tail.[1] Females have a head and body length of about 27 cm (11 in) with a 41.3 cm (16.3 in) tail. Collins' squirrel monkeys eat palm fruits, legumes, insects, bird eggs and occasionally lizards.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Ecuadorian squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru 	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Ecuadoriansquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Ecuadorian squirrel monkey (Saimiri cassiquiarensis macrodon) is a type of squirrel monkey. It had been considered a subspecies of the Guianan squirrel monkey, Saimiri sciureus, but was elevated to a full species, S. macrodon, based on a 2009 study by Carretero-Pinzón, et al. Based on subsequent genetic research by Jessica Lynch Alfaro, et al it was again reclassified as a subspecies of Humboldt's squirrel monkey. The Ecuadorian squirrel monkey lives in the western Brazilian Amazon, as well as southern Colombia, eastern Ecuador and northern and eastern Peru. It lives in humid tropical and subtropical forest, preferring dense forest but able to live in secondary forest and disturbed forest as well. It can live at elevations up to 1,200 m (3,900 ft), but where it has been studied in Ecuador it prefers elevations under 500 m (1,600 ft). The Ecuadorian squirrel monkey has a head and body length of between 25 and 32 cm (9.8 and 12.6 in) with a tail length between 34 and 44 cm (13 and 17 in). Males weigh between 885 and 1,380 g (31.2 and 48.7 oz) and females weigh between 590 and 1,150 g (21 and 41 oz). Its coloration is similar to that of the Guianan squirrel monkey but its fur is darker.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Bare-eared squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Bareearedsquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The bare-eared squirrel monkey (Saimiri ustus) is a squirrel monkey endemic to Brazil and possibly eastern Bolivia.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black-capped squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	 Bolivia, Brazil and Peru	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackcappedsquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black-capped squirrel monkey (Saimiri boliviensis) is a South American squirrel monkey, found in Bolivia, Brazil and Peru. This South American monkey can be found in numerous zoos (with over 80 zoos keeping them in Europe alone, the majority of them being of the Bolivian subspecies) around the world, including the Ellen Trout Zoo, London Zoo, Apenheul Primate Park, Copenhagen Zoo, Zurich Zoo and Auckland Zoo. Black capped squirrel monkeys are flexible omnivores, with diets including insects, fruits, flowers, eggs, and even small vertebrates (NeuroImage, Academic Press).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black squirrel monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Brazil	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blacksquirrelmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black squirrel monkey (Saimiri vanzolinii), also known as the blackish squirrel monkey or black-headed squirrel monkey, is a small New World primate, endemic to the central Amazon in Brazil. It largely resembles the female of the far more common Bolivian squirrel monkey, though the latter lacks the black central back. This squirrel monkey has one of the most restricted geographical distributions for a primate, living in várzea forest in the confluence of the Japura and Solimões rivers. Its entire range is within the Mamirauá Sustainable Development Reserve. It resides in the reserve with two other Saimiri species. It is a social primate that travels with other black squirrel monkeys in large troops within its habitat. Its small size makes it an easy target for its predators; however, it may resist predators when it travels in large troops. Its species overall has positive effects on the economy. Black squirrel monkeys are small primates. They have blackish-gray fur over most of their body except for their legs and stomach. Their legs can be yellow or have a reddish tint. Their stomachs will have a yellow tint. They have short and dense fur everywhere except for certain areas on the face. They lack hair in the areas of the nostrils and lips, and the skin is black in these areas. Black squirrel monkeys tend to be 27 to 32 centimeters in length not including the length of their tails.[6] Their full length, including their tails, can be about 40 centimeters longer than their length without their tails. Male black squirrel monkeys range in weight anywhere from 1.4 to 2.7 pounds. Female black squirrel monkeys have a weight range of 1.4 to 1.9 pounds.	</Info>
  </Monkey>

</ArrayOfMonkey>