<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Allen's swamp monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Central Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Allensswampmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Allen's swamp monkey (Allenopithecus nigroviridis) is a primate species categorized in its own genus Allenopithecus in the Old World monkey family. Phylogenetically, it is a sister clade to the guenons, but differs in dentition and habits. Allen's swamp monkey was named after American zoologist Joel Asaph Allen. \n This monkey is a rather strongly built animal. Its skin is grey-green at the top side. Its face is reddish with long hair bundles at the cheeks. The slight webbing of the fingers and toes point to its partially aquatic way of life. Allen's swamp monkey can reach a full body length from 45 to 60 cm, with a roughly 50-cm-long tail. Males, weighing up to 6 kg, are substantially larger than the females (up to 3.5 kg).	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Angolan talapoin	</Name>
    <Location>	Central Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Angolantalapoin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Angolan talapoin (Miopithecus talapoin), also known as the southern talapoin, is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. \n Talapoins are the smallest species of Old-World monkeys.The fur of the Angolan talapoin is coarsely banded yellow-and-black on the back and flanks and white or greyish white on the chest and belly. The head is round and short-snouted with a hairless face which has a black nose skin bordering the face. The scrotum is coloured pink medially and blue laterally. \n They show mild sexual dimorphism in body size, the average head and body length is 40 centimetres (16 in), the average tail length is 52.5 centimetres (20.7 in) and the average weight is 1,380 grams (49 oz) for males and 1,120 grams (40 oz) for females.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Gabon talapoin	</Name>
    <Location>	Central Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Gabontalapoin.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Gabon talapoin (Miopithecus ogouensis), also known as the northern talapoin, is a small species of African monkey in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in riparian habitats in Cameroon, Equatorial Guinea, Gabon, and western Republic of the Congo and far western Democratic Republic of Congo. It may have been introduced to Fernando Poo and the Canary Islands. \n  Unlike the related Angolan talapoin, the Gabon talapoin has flesh-coloured (not blackish) ears and facial skin.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Patas monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	West Africa and East Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>PatasMonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The patas monkey (Erythrocebus patas), also known as the wadi monkey or hussar monkey, is a ground-dwelling monkey distributed over semi-arid areas of West Africa, and into East Africa. It was formerly considered the only member of the genus Erythrocebus, but the Blue Nile patas monkey, previously synonymized with this species, was resurrected in 2018. The male patas monkey grows to 60 cm (24 in) to 87 cm (34 in) in length, excluding the tail, which measures 75 cm (30 in). Adult males are considerably larger than adult females, which average 49 cm (19 in) in length. Adult males average 12.4 kg (27.3 lb) and adult females 6.5 kg (14.3 lb), showing a high degree of sexual dimorphism. Reaching speeds of 55 km/h (34 mph), it is the fastest runner among the primates. The life span in the wild can be up to about 20 years.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Green monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	West Africa 	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Greenmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The green monkey (Chlorocebus sabaeus), also known as the sabaeus monkey or the callithrix monkey, is an Old World monkey with golden-green fur and pale hands and feet. The tip of the tail is golden yellow as are the backs of the thighs and cheek whiskers. It does not have a distinguishing band of fur on the brow, like other Chlorocebus species, and males have a pale blue scrotum. Some authorities consider this and all of the members of the genus Chlorocebus to be a single widespread species, Chlorocebus aethiops.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Grivet	</Name>
    <Location>	East Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Grivet.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The grivet (Chlorocebus aethiops), also known as African green monkey and savannah monkey is an Old World monkey with long white tufts of hair along the sides of the face. Some authorities consider this and all of the members of the genus Chlorocebus to be a single species, Cercopithecus aethiops. As here defined, the grivet is restricted to Ethiopia, Sudan, Djibouti and Eritrea. In the southern part of its range, it comes into contact with the closely related vervet monkey (C. pygerythrus) and Bale Mountains vervet (C. djamdjamensis). Hybridization between them is possible, and may present a threat to the vulnerable Bale Mountains vervet. Unlike that species, the grivet is common and rated as Least Concern by the IUCN.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Bale Mountains vervet	</Name>
    <Location>	East Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>BaleMountainsvervet.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Bale Mountains vervet (Chlorocebus djamdjamensis) is a terrestrial Old World monkey endemic to Ethiopia, found in the bamboo forests of the Bale Mountains. It was originally described as a subspecies of the grivet (Chlorocebus aethiops). All species in Chlorocebus were formerly in the genus Cercopithecus. The Bale Mountains Vervet is one of the least known primates in Africa. The Bale Mountains Vervet avoid tree-dominated and bush land areas as their habitat. These monkeys mainly reside in the bamboo forest (Odubullu Forest) of the Bale mountain due their dietary specialization on bamboo, however, other factors such as climate, forest history, soil quality, and disease could are likely to play a role in their choice to inhibit this area. The Bale Mountains Vervet have a very quiet behavior and tend to flee when coming across a human being.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tantalus monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Central Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Tantalusmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The tantalus monkey (Chlorocebus tantalus) is an Old World monkey from Africa that ranges from Ghana to Sudan. It was originally described as a subspecies of the grivet (Chlorocebus aethiops). All species in Chlorocebus were formerly in the genus Cercopithecus. It is a common species with a wide range, and the International Union for Conservation of Nature has rated its conservation status as being of 'least concern'. A medium-sized species, the tantalus monkey has a black face and a long tail. There is a distinctive undulating white or yellowish browband above the eyes. The cheeks and temples are white, the long hairs being swept backwards and often covering the ears in older individuals. The crown and dorsal surface of the body is grizzled and greenish or golden. The underparts are white and the tail and outer surfaces of the limbs grey. The tail may have a whitish tip. The male is larger than the female and has a bright blue scrotum surrounded by orange hairs.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Vervet monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	East Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Vervetmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The vervet monkey (Chlorocebus pygerythrus), or simply vervet, is an Old World monkey of the family Cercopithecidae native to Africa. The term 'vervet' is also used to refer to all the members of the genus Chlorocebus. The five distinct subspecies can be found mostly throughout Southern Africa, as well as some of the eastern countries. Vervets were introduced to Florida, St. Kitts, and Cape Verde. These mostly herbivorous monkeys have black faces and grey body hair color, ranging in body length from about 50 centimetres (20 in) for males to about 40 centimetres (16 in) for females. In addition to behavioral research on natural populations, vervet monkeys serve as a nonhuman primate model for understanding genetic and social behaviors of humans. They have been noted for having human-like characteristics, such as hypertension, anxiety, and social and dependent alcohol use. Vervets live in social groups ranging from 10 to 70 individuals, with males moving to other groups at the time of sexual maturity. The most significantstudies done on vervet monkeys involve their communication and alarm calls, specifically in regard to kin and group recognition and particular predator sightings.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Malbrouck	</Name>
    <Location>	Central Africa and South Central Africa	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Malbrouck.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The malbrouck (Chlorocebus cynosuros) is an Old World primate from Africa that belongs to the genus Chlorocebus. The species is sometimes classified as a subspecies of the vervet monkey (C. pygerythrus), or of the widespread grivet (C. aethiops). The malbrouck is a slim, agile primate with long limbs and a long tail. The fur is olive-grey. The breast and underparts are white, as well as the cheeks and eyebrows, which surround the bald, pale-blotched face. The eyes are brown. The genitals are brightly colored; the scrotum of the male is blue, the penis is red. Males are about 20% larger than females.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
<Monkey> <Name>	Dryas monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Dryasmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>The Dryas monkey (Cercopithecus dryas), also known as Salonga monkey, ekele, or inoko, is a little-known species of guenon found only in the Congo Basin, restricted to the left bank of the Congo River. It is now established that the animals that had been classified as Cercopithecus salongo (the common name being Zaire Diana monkey) were in fact Dryas monkeys. Some older sources treat the Dryas monkey as a subspecies of the Diana monkey and classify it as C. diana dryas, but it is geographically isolated from any known Diana monkey population. While the Dryas monkey had been considered data deficient, evidence suggests it is very rare and its total population possibly numbers fewer than 200 individuals. Consequently, its status was changed to critically endangered in the 2008 IUCN Red List. Along with being listed by the IUCN, this species is also listed on Appendix II of CITES. However, in January 2019 the IUCN status was changed to endangered following the discovery of this species at eight locations in Lomami National Park.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey> <Name>	Diana monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Dianamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>The Diana monkey ranges from 40 to 55 cm in length, excluding its tail, which is of a uniform 3–4 cm diameter and 50–75 cm long. Adults weigh between 4–7 kg. Individual Diana monkeys may live for up to 20 years. They are generally black or dark grey, but have a white throat, crescent-shaped browband, ruff and beard; the browband gave the species its common name, since it was held to resemble the crescent on the brow of the goddess Diana. The monkeys' underarms are also white, and they have a white stripe down their thighs, while the backs of their thighs, and their lower backs, are a chestnut colour. Apart from the browband, ruff and beard, and some fringes on their limbs, their fur is rough and tough. The term “old-world monkey” refers to the family of monkeys known as Cercopithecoidea and the Diana monkey is only 1 species out of the 148 that are a part of this family.Like most primates, Diana monkeys can always carry diseases that can be communicated to humans, like yellow fever and tuberculosis, but they are not important carriers of these. The species is regarded as endangered by the IUCN as well as by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the chief dangers to them being habitat destruction (they are now virtually confined to coastal areas) and hunting for bushmeat. Two taxa formerly considered subspecies of the Diana monkey have recently been elevated to full species status: the roloway monkey (C. roloway) is found in Côte d'Ivoire and Ghana, and the Dryas monkey (C. dryas) found in the DR Congo.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Roloway monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Rolowaymonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>The Diana monkey (Cercopithecus diana) is an Old World monkey found in West Africa, from Sierra Leone to Côte d'Ivoire. The roloway monkey (Cercopithecus roloway) is an endangered species of Old World monkey endemic to tropical West Africa. It was previously considered a subspecies of the Diana monkey (C. diana). It is classified as Endangered due to habitat loss and continued hunting for the bushmeat trade. The roloway monkey is similar to other species of guenons. Like its closest relative, C. diana, its face and much of its fur are black, but is distinguished by its lengthy beard and broader diadem-like browband. It has a white beard, chest, and throat; white stripe runs along each thigh and a deep reddish or orange patch is on its back. On the inside of the thighs, the fur is whitish, yellowish, or reddish. The body length ranges from 40 to 55 cm, with a tail of 50=75 cm. Its weight is between 4 and 7 kg.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Greater spot-nosed monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa and Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Greaterspotnosedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The greater spot-nosed monkey or putty-nosed monkey (Cercopithecus nictitans) is one of the smallest Old World monkeys. It is a guenon of the C. mitis group, native to West Africa and living to some extent in rain forests, but more often in the transition zone between rain forest and savannah. It is primarily arboreal and often associates with monkeys of other species. Both their common names come from the monkeys' prominent white nose. The greater spot-nosed monkey lives in groups consisting of one adult male, a number of adult females, and their dependent offspring.[4] Little recent research has been conducted into its behaviour, and most has concentrated on its auditory communication. Males use three call types which have been described as 'booms', 'pyows', and 'hacks'. These are used in a number of contexts including as alarm calls. As in some other species of monkeys, the acoustical structure of greater spot-nosed monkey alarm calls it has been argued to vary according to the kind of predator spotted. The monkey reportedly combines different sounds into a sequence, which has an entirely different meaning from the sounds out of which it is made. For instance, the sound 'pyow' alone means another animal, like a leopard, is lurking nearby, and 'hack' means a flying animal, like an eagle, is flying nearby, but when the two are combined, as in the sequence 'pyow pyow hack hack hack hack', they have an entirely different meaning: Let's get out of here and move to another place.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Golden monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Goldenmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>The golden monkey (Cercopithecus kandti) is a species of Old World monkey found in the Virunga volcanic mountains of Central Africa, including four national parks: Mgahinga, in south-west Uganda; Volcanoes, in north-west Rwanda and Virunga and Kahuzi-Biéga, in the eastern Democratic Republic of Congo. It is restricted to highland forest, especially near bamboo. This species was previously thought to be a subspecies of the blue monkey (Cercopithecus mitis), and the two are similar overall, but the golden monkey has a golden-orange patch on the upper flanks and back. Not much is known about the golden monkey's behaviour. It lives in social groups of up to 30 individuals. Its diet consists mainly of bamboo, leaves and fruit, though it is also thought to eat insects. Due to the gradual destruction of their habitat and recent wars in their limited habitat, the golden monkey is listed as endangered on the IUCN Red List.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Sykes' monkey	</Name>	<Location>	South Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Sykesmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>Sykes' monkey (Cercopithecus albogularis), also known as the white-throated monkey or Samango monkey, is an Old World monkey found between Ethiopia and South Africa, including south and east Democratic Republic of Congo. It is named after English naturalist Colonel William Henry Sykes (1790-1872), and has been considered conspecific with the blue monkey (which in turn has included the golden and silver monkey), but has a large white patch on the throat and upper chest, and a grizzled (not blackish) cap.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>MonaMonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>The mona monkey (Cercopithecus mona) is an Old World monkey that lives in western Africa between Ghana and Cameroon. The mona monkey can also be found on the island of Grenada as it was transported to the island aboard slave ships headed to the New World during the 18th century. This guenon lives in groups of up to thirty-five in forests. It mainly feeds on fruit, but sometimes eats insects and leaves. The mona monkey has brown agouti fur with a white rump. Its tail and legs are black and the face is blue-grey with a dark stripe across the face. The mona monkey carries food in cheek pouches.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Campbell's mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Campbellsmonamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>Campbell's mona monkey, also known as Campbell's guenon and Campbell's monkey (Cercopithecus campbelli) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae found in the Ivory Coast, Gambia, Ghana, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Liberia, Senegal, and Sierra Leone. It was named for Henry Dundas Campbell, in 1838. Lowe's mona monkey was previously considered a subspecies of Campbell's mona monkey. The International Union for Conservation of Nature has rated this species as being of least concern because it has a wide range and is able to adapt to degraded habitats.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Lowe's mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Lowesmonamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Lowe's mona monkey (Cercopithecus lowei) is an Old World monkey in the family Cercopithecidae found from the Ivory Coast to Ghana. It was previously classified as a subspecies of Campbell's mona monkey C. campbelli.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Crested mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Crestedmonamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The crested mona monkey, also known as the crowned guenon, crowned monkey, golden-bellied guenon, or golden-bellied monkey, (Cercopithecus pogonias), is a species of African primate in the family Cercopithecidae found in west central Africa. The crested mona monkey is a medium-sized, long tailed arboreal monkey with the females being smaller than the males but showing similar colouration and pattern of coat. They have a brown coat speckled with grey which becomes black on its lower arms and legs and on the base of its long tail. The rump, belly and the insides of the legs are golden-yellow contrasting with the rest of the fur. The males have a distinctive blue scrotum. Their faces are mainly dark blue with a pink muzzle. Around the face the fur is yellow marked with a wide black stripes which runs from the beside the eyes over to the temples and across the centre of the forehead where it forms the characteristic small crest which gives this species its common name.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Wolf's mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Wolfsmonamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Wolf's mona monkey (Cercopithecus wolfi), also called Wolf's guenon, is a colourful Old World monkey in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in central Africa, primarily between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Uganda. It lives in primary and secondary lowland rainforest and swamp forest. Guenons, the largest group of African primates, are very colorful. Their color is used in intraspecific communication for recognizing individuals, species, and potential mates. Wolf's mona monkey is dark grey with a red 'saddle' on its back. The pelage depends on the subspecies. C. wolfi wolfi has a chestnut-colored patch on the middle of its back. Its arms are black and legs are red. It has a yellow underside, occasionally with an orange stripe down its flanks. Its cheek whiskers are yellow, speckled with black, and its ear tufts are red. C. wolfi elegans has a back which is gradually browner towards the rump. Its forearms are black, and its upper arms have a pale speckling. Its legs are light gray, while its underside is white. Its cheek whiskers are white, with dark speckling that increases near the base.[6] Its ear tufts are white. The male's scrotum is blue. Wolf's mona monkey is also sexually dimorphic in size. Males weigh, on average, almost twice as much as females, 4.5 kilograms (10 lb) and 2.5 kilograms (5.5 lb) respectively. Its small size makes it susceptible to predators, especially the crowned eagle and the leopard.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Dent's mona monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Dentsmonamonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Dent's mona monkey (Cercopithecus denti) is an Old World monkey in the family Cercopithecidae found in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, the Congo, Rwanda, western Uganda, and the Central African Republic. It was previously classified as a subspecies of Wolf's mona monkey C. wolf.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Lesser spot-nosed monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>LesserspotnosedMonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The lesser spot-nosed monkey, lesser spot-nosed guenon, lesser white-nosed guenon, or lesser white-nosed monkey (Cercopithecus petaurista) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Ivory Coast, Ghana, Guinea, Liberia, Sierra Leone, Togo, Guinea-Bissau, and possibly Senegal. This is a small arboreal species with a long tail. The face is black with a white nose spot. A white stripe extends from the temple to below the ear. The crown, back, outer side of the limbs and upper surface of the tail are olive-green or khaki. In some forms, the middle and lower back have a reddish tinge. The individual hairs, especially on the crown, are flecked with black and yellow. The underparts, inner side of the limbs and underside of the tail are white or cream.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	White-throated guenon	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Whitethroatedguenon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The white-throated guenon (Cercopithecus erythrogaster), also known as the red-bellied monkey and the red-bellied guenon, is a diurnal primate that lives on trees of rainforests or tropical areas of Nigeria and Benin. The white-throated guenon is usually a frugivore but insects, leaves, and crops are also in its diet. It usually lives in small groups of four to five individual monkeys however, there have been groups of 30 discovered, and in cases, some males wander alone. It is arboreal, living in moist tropical forest and the wettest parts of dry tropical forest, however it can also be found in secondary bush and old farmland. Males weigh from 3.5–4.5 kg and females weigh 2–4 kg. Females give birth to one offspring, which is a factor of decreasing population. The white-throated guenon was once considered extinct due to constant hunting for the fur of its unique red belly and white front legs. Yet, a small group was found near the Niger River in 1988.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Sclater's guenon	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Sclatersguenon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Sclater's guenon (Cercopithecus sclateri), also known as Sclater's monkey and the Nigerian monkey, is an Old World monkey that was first described by Reginald Innes Pocock in 1904 and named after Philip Sclater. It is an arboreal and diurnal primate that lives in the forests of southern Nigeria. It should not be confused with the closely related species, the white-throated guenon (Cercopithecus erythrogaster), which occurs in Nigeria and Benin. Sclater's guenon was formerly classified as a subspecies of the red-eared guenon (C. erythrotis). The diet of Sclater's guenon is unknown. The species is likely primarily a frugivore that supplements its diet with other plant parts and insects, based on data from closely related species. Sclater's guenon was thought to be nearly extinct until the late 1980s. The species is now known to occur in several isolated populations between the Niger and Cross Rivers in southern Nigeria. This region falls in the Guinean Forests of the West Africa biodiversity hotspot.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Red-eared guenon	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Redearedguenon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The red-eared guenon, red-eared monkey, or russet-eared guenon (Cercopithecus erythrotis) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Cameroon, Equatorial Guinea, and Nigeria. Its natural habitat is subtropical or tropical moist lowland forests. It is threatened by habitat loss, illegal bushmeat hunting and pet trade. The red-eared guenon is a small, colourful monkey with distinctive facial markings which involve blue fur around its eyes, a brick-red nose and ears, and yellow cheeks. The silky fur on the body consists of banded brown and pale hairs with grey limbs and a long, red tail. The long tails are partially prehensile and are used by infants to cling to the female. The red eared guenon is an unobtrusive species which produces a quiet trill, unlike the loud long distance calls made by other guenons. Males average 420mm head and bodylength, with a 609mm long tail, females are smaller with a mean head and body length of 384mm and an average tail length of 553mm.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Moustached guenon	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Moustachedguenon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The moustached guenon or moustached monkey (Cercopithecus cephus) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Angola, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Republic of the Congo, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Equatorial Guinea, and Gabon.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Red-tailed monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Redtailedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The red-tailed monkey, also known as the black-cheeked white-nosed monkey, red-tailed guenon, redtail monkey, or Schmidt's guenon (Cercopithecus ascanius) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Angola, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Kenya, Rwanda, South Sudan, Tanzania, Uganda, Zambia, and possibly Burundi. The red-tailed monkey is usually black, red, or orange. Although native to this region, it has spread north and south as well as it can survive in different habitats and under different conditions. It is a distinct creature in its habitats and is gradually becoming endangered due to deforestation and over-exploitation through hunting and predation. The red-tailed monkey is named as it sounds, for its red coloration of the tail's underside as well as the bi-coloration of the tail as the reddish color increases from the base to the tip. There are other features characteristic to this mammal as well such as the white nose and cheeks in the midst of black or dark grey body fur. Red-tailed monkeys also have very large, elastic cheeks which are used in gathering food and storing it in their mouths for safety.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	L'Hoest's monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>LHoestsmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The L'Hoest's monkey (Allochrocebus lhoesti), or mountain monkey, is a guenon found in the upper eastern Congo basin. They mostly live in mountainous forest areas in small, female-dominated groups. They have a dark coat and can be distinguished by a characteristic white beard. C. lhoesti has a short, dark brown coat, with a chestnut color across the back and a dark belly. Its cheeks are light gray with a pale moustache. It has a characteristic and prominent white bib, In body length it is 12.5 to 27 inches (32 to 69 cm), with a 19-to-39-inch (48 to 99 cm) tail. The male weighs about 6 kilograms (13 lb), while the smaller female weighs 3.5 kilograms (7.7 lb). Its tail is long and hook-shaped at the end. They are born fully coated and with their eyes open.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Preuss's monkey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Preusssmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Preuss's monkey (Allochrocebus preussi), also known as Preuss's guenon, is a diurnal primate that lives terrestrially in mountainous (up to 2500 m) forests of eastern Nigeria, western Cameroon and Bioko in Equatorial Guinea. It was formerly classified as a subspecies of the L'Hoest's monkey (A. lhoesti). Pruess's monkey is currently classified as a member of the genus Allochrocebus. It was formerly considered a member of the genus Cercopithecus. The diet of Preuss's monkey is primarily fruit, leaves and insects, although the species occasionally raids human crops. It is darkish in coloration with a white chin, and adult males have a blue scrotum. Preuss's monkeys weigh up to 10 kg. Troops consist of one adult male and several females and adolescents, averaging 17 total per troop. Females give birth to a single offspring about once every three years. The young mature at 4 years and live to be an average of 31 years. Preuss's monkey is an endangered species, due to habitat loss and hunting. It is one of the species that live in the Guinean Forests of the West Africa Biodiversity Hotspot.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Sun-tailed monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Suntailedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The sun-tailed monkey (Allochrocebus solatus) from Gabon is one of the least studied primates in its habitat. It was discovered as a new species in 1988, and is classified as a guenon, which is a member of the genus Cercopithecus, but was subsequently moved to the genus Allochrocebus. It is closely related to A. preussi and A. Ihoesti, which has been determined by chromosomal analysis. Sun-Tailed monkeys prefer areas with lots of shade and dense vegetation. However, even after small amounts of logging activity, populations can be unaffected. Much of their diet remains unknown and it is still being studied, but they do prefer to eat fruit. Their social groups are made up of one male and multiple females. Generally, the sun-tailed monkey is less aggressive towards related individuals, which is noteworthy because it has been found that, in other primate species, aggression rates towards related individuals are generally as high or higher than aggression rates towards non-related individuals. Within their social groups, individual monkeys show preference for their mothers over their fathers, and are overall less aggressive to other monkeys that they are associated with spatially.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Hamlyn's monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Hamlynsmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Hamlyn's monkey (Cercopithecus hamlyni), also known as the owl-faced monkey, is a species of Old World monkey that inhabits the bamboo and primary rainforests of the Congo. This species is exceedingly rare and known only from a few specimens; little is known about it. However these specimens tend to be widely dispersed throughout the eastern part of Congo, from the Epulu River to the Lukuga River and from the Congo River to the Kabale Forest, with one example in northwestern Rwanda. Geographically it corresponds quite closely to another species of monkey, L'Hoest's monkey C. lhoesti. It travels on the ground, and researchers think that it may be awake primarily by night. Schwarz (1928) grouped this species with C. l'hoesti, while Elliot (1913) noted its distinctive cusp pattern on the third molar, and reassigned it to a separate genus, Rhinostigma. This he believed to be an intermediate between Cercopithecus and Cercocebus. Hamlyn's monkey has one subspecies other than the nominate. In weight, the male is much larger than the female, with the average adult weighing 7 to 10 kg, while females weigh on average 4.5 to 6 kg.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	De Brazza's monkey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>DeBrazzasmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The DeBrazza's monkey (Cercopithecus neglectus) is an Old World monkey endemic to the riverine and swamp forests of central Africa. The largest species in the guenon family, it is one of the most widespread arboreal African primates. Aside from size, it can be differentiated from other cercopithecus monkeys by its orange diadem and white beard. Due to its cryptic nature, the species is not well documented in all of its habitats but has shown unique traits such as pair-bonding and aggressive behavior towards other guenons. The De Brazza's monkey is the most sexually dimorphic species of guenon; males weigh around 7 kilograms, while females weigh around 4 kilograms. Adults have grey agouti fur with a reddish-brown back, black limbs and tail, and a white rump. Both sexes have cheek pouches they use to carry food while they forage. Males have a distinct blue scrotum, while females have a red perianal region and visible nipples. Juveniles lack the darker colors on the extremities that is characteristic of adults, but retain the whites stripes and red rump while infants are a uniform brown agouti with only a small beard. The white muzzle and beard, along with an orange crescent on its forehead and white stripes on its thighs distinguish it from other guenons. Due to this distinctive appearance, the monkey is sometimes referred to as the "Ayatollah Monkey" after the similarly-bearded Grand Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini.	</Info>	</Monkey>


</ArrayOfMonkey>