<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
<Monkey>	<Name>	Olive colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>OliveColobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The olive colobus monkey (Procolobus verus), also known as the green colobus or Van Beneden's colobus, is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. Its English name refers to its dull olive upperparts. It is the smallest example of all colobine monkeys and is rarely observed in its natural habitat because of its cryptic coloration and secretive nature. It is found in the rain forests of West Africa, ranging from southern Sierra Leone to Nigeria. As of 2019, the IUCN Red List classifies the olive colobus as vulnerable (previously near threatened), with the cause of its decline attributed to habitat loss and hunting. Though much of the land within the range of the olive colobus has been affected by human activities, it retains its ability to thrive in small degraded forest fragments. //n Procolobus verus is a small-bodied mammal with an average body weight of 4.6 kilograms for males and 4.1 kilograms for females. The olive colobus are greenish-brown in color with the hairs transitioning from greenish-yellow at the root, and becoming darker towards the tip. The under side of the olive colobus is lighter in color and the hairs found on the face are stiff and dark. Their coloration allows them to stay camouflaged within the trees reducing the risk of predation. These monkeys have a unique feature in that their thumb is severely reduced on their forefeet, while the hind feet retain five digits. The feet of the olive colobus are also abnormally large compared to other African colobine species.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Western red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Westernredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The western red colobus (Piliocolobus badius), also known as the bay red colobus, rust red colobus or Upper Guinea red colobus, is a species of Old World monkey found in West African forests from Senegal to Ghana. All other species of red colobuses have formerly been considered subspecies of P. badius. It is often hunted by the common chimpanzee. In 1994, western red colobus monkeys infected many chimpanzees with Ebola virus when they were hunted and eaten by the chimpanzees. //n The western red colobus grows to a head-and-body length of 450 to 670 mm (18 to 26 in) with a tail of 520 to 800 mm (20 to 31 in), and a weight of between 5 and 11 kg (11 and 24 lb). It has red or chestnut-brown head and limbs and black, slatey-grey or dark brown upper parts. It does not have long fringes of hair, or tufts of hair on the tail. Compared to monkeys in the genus Colobus, the nostrils are V-shaped, the digits are long and the big toe short.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Temminck's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Temmincksredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Temminck's red colobus (Piliocolobus basius temminckii) is a type of red colobus monkey from Senegal, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau and the Gambia. It has historically been regarded as a subspecies of the western red colobus (Piliocolobus badius), and the Integrated Taxonomic Information System maintains this classification, but many recent taxonomies classify it as a separate species (Piliocolobus temminckii).//n Temminck's red colobus generally lives in dry deciduous and gallery forests. In Senegal it also lives in savannah. No other red colobus lives in savannah. The use of savannah and open areas may be a recent adaptation to deforestation, since researchers in the 1970s always found Temminck's red colobus in tall, dense forest. Temminck's red colobus living in savannahs often associate with green monkeys, and sometimes also associate with patas monkeys and bushbucks for defense against predators. Temminck's red colobus differs from the Western red colobus in that the Western red colobus lives in rainforest rather than dry forest and savannah, which may explain differences in behavior. //n The majority of its diet consists of fruit and leaves. Seeds, flowers, buds, bark and nuts account for most of the rest of the diet. //n Temminck's red colobus is listed as endangered on the IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. Primary threats include deforestation and hunting.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Miss Waldron's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>MissWaldronsredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Miss Waldron's red colobus (Piliocolobus waldronae) is a species of the red colobus native to West Africa. It had previously been described as a subspecies of the western red colobus, P. badius. It has not been officially sighted since 1978 and was considered extinct in 2000. However, new evidence suggests that a very small number of these monkeys may be living in the southeast corner of Côte d'Ivoire. The IUCN Red List notes Miss Waldron's red colobus as critically endangered. //n Miss Waldron's red colobus was discovered in December 1933 by Willoughby P. Lowe, a British Museum (Natural History) collector who had shot eight specimens of the animal. Lowe named it after a fellow museum employee, Miss F. Waldron, a colleague on the expedition.//n Black fur covers the majority of Miss Waldron's red colobus, but a distinctive pattern of bright red fur can be found on its forehead and thighs, allowing it to be distinguished from conspecifics. An Old World monkey, it grows to a height of about 3 feet (1 m), with a head that is small for its frame. No photograph of a living Miss Waldron's red colobus is known to exist.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Pennant's colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Pennantscolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Pennant's colobus or Pennant's red colobus (Piliocolobus pennantii) is a species of tree-dwelling primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to tropical Central Africa. Three subspecies have traditionally been recognised but its distribution is peculiarly disjunct and has been considered a biogeographical puzzle. with one population on the island of Bioko (Equatorial Guinea), a second in the Niger River Delta in southern Nigeria, and a third in east-central Republic of Congo. It is found in rainforests and marshy forests. It is threatened by habitat loss and hunting for bushmeat. One subspecies, bouvieri, is rated as Critically Endangered; although it was last photographically documented in 2015, it may be on the brink of extinction. //n Pennant's red colobus is a moderate-sized species with a head and body length of 53 to 63 centimetres (21 to 25 in) and a tail of 60 to 70 centimetres (24 to 28 in). It weighs about 7 to 10 kilograms (15 to 22 lb). It has a small head and robust body with long limbs. The long fingers have a powerful grip for climbing about among the branches, but it has no thumbs. The colouration varies between subspecies, being black or some shade of brown with chestnut-brown or reddish face, arms and legs and pale underparts. The black face is crowned with long hair, usually parted in the middle. Red colobus monkeys have a long tail used only for balancing which is not prehensile.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Niger Delta red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>NigerDeltaredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Niger Delta red colobus (Piliocolobus epieni) is a critically endangered species of colobus monkey endemic to the western part of the Niger Delta. It is threatened by hunting and habitat loss. //n The Niger Delta red colobus is black on top from the head to the rump, becoming orange-brown on the sides and outer legs. The undersides and inner legs, and most of the arms are white. The hands and feet are black. The tail is red-brown on top and chestnut or maroon below, becoming darker towards the tip. It has white whiskers.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Preuss's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Preusssredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Preuss's red colobus (Piliocolobus preussi) is a red colobus primate species endemic to the Cross-Sanaga Rivers ecoregion. An important population occurs in Korup National Park, Southwest Province, Cameroon, but the species' distribution is localized (groups are frequently encountered near the main tourist camps). The species is considered present in adjacent Cross River National Park - Oban Division in Nigeria and hunter reports suggest that few groups remain in Nkwende Hills and Nta Ali Forest Reserve in the broader Korup region. A population is also present in Ebo forest, Littoral Province of Cameroon. //n Preuss's red colobus has a black head, a black back ticked with orange, and bright red tail, limbs and cheeks.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Zanzibar red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Zanzibar	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Zanzibarredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Zanzibar red colobus (Piliocolobus kirkii) is a species of red colobus monkey endemic to Unguja, the main island of the Zanzibar Archipelago, off the coast of Tanzania. It is also known as Kirk's red colobus after Sir John Kirk, the British Resident of Zanzibar who first brought it to the attention of zoological science. It is now classified as an endangered species and in the mid-1990s was adopted as the flagship species for conservation in Zanzibar. The population is still decreasing, and conservationists are attempting to work with the local government to devise a proper, effective strategy to protect the population and habitat. Challenges include the species' habitat, which is limited to the archipelago. The species has been reclassified three times; it was previously in the genus Colobus, then in the genus Procolobus, and later in the genus Piliocolobus. //n This Old World monkey's coat ranges from dark red to black, accented with a black stripe along the shoulders and arms, and a pale underside. Its black face is crowned with long, white hair, and features a distinguishing pink mark on its lips and nose. Also, the Zanzibar red colobus has a long tail used only for balancing — it is not prehensile. Sexual dimorphism is generally decreased in the species, meaning the females have little difference in their body size and colour from their male counterparts. Females usually outnumber the males in their groups. The species has a notably small cranium and rotund body shape, with males potentially reaching over 12 kg and females, 10 kg. In adults, highly differentiated facial features help them to distinguish each other in a group. //n The word 'colobus' comes from Greek ekolobóse, meaning "he cut short", and is so named because of the significant reduction in size, or complete lack of an opposable thumb in comparison to other primates. To make up for this, they have four long digits that align to form a strong hook, allowing them to easily grasp branches and climb. //n Locals on the island have called the Zanzibar red colobus kima punju which means 'poison monkey' in Swahili because of their strong smell unlike other monkeys. This has caused people to hold negative views of the monkey and even to say it has an evil influence on trees on which they feed, ultimately killing the trees.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Foa's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	 Democratic Republic of the Congo	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Foasredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Foa's red colobus or Central African red colobus (Piliocolobus foai) is a species of red colobus monkey found in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. //n Foa's red colobus has long red and black fur on its back and head, with light underparts. Males have a body length excluding tail of between 50 and 69 centimetres (20 and 27 in) with a tail that is between 62 and 67 centimetres (24 and 26 in) long. Males typically weigh between 9 and 13 kilograms (20 and 29 lb) and females typically weigh between 7 and 9 kilograms (15 and 20 lb). It has smaller teeth than most other red colobus species.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Ugandan red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	 Uganda and Tanzania	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Ugandanredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Ugandan red colobus (Piliocolobus tephrosceles) or ashy red colobus is an endangered species of red colobus monkey, recognised as a distinct species since 2001. There is disagreement however over taxonomy with many considering the Ugandan red colobus to be a subspecies (Procolobus rufomitratus tephrosceles). The Ugandan red colobus is an Old World monkey which is found in 5 different locations across Uganda and Tanzania. //n The Ugandan red colobus has a rust-red cap with a dark grey to black face, although infants are born with completely black faces. There is more variation amongst the coat colours of the Ugandan red colobus with back colour ranging from black to dark grey through to a reddish brown. The sides of the body and the arms and legs are a light grey. They have very long dark to light brown tails which they rely on for balancing when climbing and leaping through the canopy. The Ugandan red colobus has dark grey to black hands and feet and their feet are very long which helps them leap large distances. The Ugandan red colobus grooming in Kibale National Park, Uganda. //n The Ugandan red colobus, like all colobus monkeys, has thumbs which are so reduced in size they are almost absent. It is thought this feature may help in brachiation when moving through the canopy. //n There is strong sexual dimorphism; the males are much larger than the females. The average male weighs around 10.5 kg and the females weigh around 7 kg.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Tana River red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Kenya	</Location>	<ImageUrl>TanaRiverredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Tana River red colobus (Piliocolobus rufomitratus), also called the eastern red colobus, is a highly endangered species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to a narrow zone of gallery forest near the Tana River in southeastern Kenya. //n The Tana River red colobus had been considered one of The World's 25 Most Endangered Primates. It was, together with the equally endangered Tana River mangabey, the main reason for the creation of the Tana River Primate Reserve in 1978, but human encroachment within this reserve continues. Recently, it has been suggested that 20,000 hectares of the Tana River Delta should be transformed into sugarcane plantations, but this has, temporarily at least, been stopped by the High Court of Kenya. Contra Groves, it was not recognized as a species separate from the Ugandan, Central African and Thollon's red colobus in the 2008 IUCN Red List. With these as subspecies, P. rufomitratus is considered to be of least concern in the 2008 IUCN Red List, while P. (r.) rufomitratus is considered endangered.//n The Tana River red colobus has been under the watch of the Tana River Primate National Reserve (TRPNR). They put a large amount of research and study into the conservation of the Tana River red colobus. They found that only 37% of the red colobuses lived inside the preservation itself, which has brought the conservation strategy into question.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Udzungwa red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Tanzania	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Udzungwaredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Uzungwa red colobus (Piliocolobus gordonorum), also known as the Udzungwa red colobus or Iringa red colobus, is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to riverine and montane forest in the Udzungwa Mountains in Tanzania. It is threatened by habitat loss.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Bouvier's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	 Republic of the Congo	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Bouviersredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Bouvier's red colobus (Piliocolobus bouvieri) is a species of colobus monkey rediscovered in the Republic of the Congo in 2015, after four decades without a confirmed sighting. //n Bouvier's red colobus has brownish-red fur on its body that is lighter than its closest relative, the Bioko red colobus (P. pennantii pennantii). Its head has a patch of black to chocolate brown fur that is smaller than that of P. p. pennantii. It has a white chin and whiskers. A black band of fur extends from above the eyes to the temples. The monkey's eyes are surround by large, pink eyerings. The tail of P. bouvieri is long in proportion to its small body and is dark brown at the root, fading to brownish-red at the tip. The fur on the species' underside is lighter than the fur on its back. Bouvier's red colobus is thought to exhibit considerable facial variation from individual to individual, varying from light flesh-colored with blackish cheeks and brows to darker tones throughout the face, excluding the nose and lips.//n Bouvier's red colobus lives in swampy forests surrounding the Congo River, between the mouths of the Alima and Oubangui Rivers. It does not show fear of humans, making it an easy target for bushmeat hunters.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Semliki red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Semlikiredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Semliki red colobus (Piliocolobus semlikiensis) is a type of red colobus monkey from central Africa. Historically it has been treated as a subspecies of the Central African red colobus (P. foai) but more recent taxonomies generally treat it as a separate species.//n The Semliki red colobus lives in ironwood forest in the portion of the northeastern Democratic Republic of the Congo between the Semliki River valley and the Ruwenzori Mountains. It may also live in a small area of Uganda. //n The Semliki Red Colobus was first described only in 1991—at which point it may have already been on the brink of extinction. This black-backed and white-bellied monkey sports an elegant long tail and striking sweeps of red coloration down its sides. The Semliki River, which connects Lake Edward to Lake Albert, flows through the famed Virunga National Park, as well as the Mt. Hoyo Reserve. Semliki Red Colobus Monkeys lived in the forests of western Uganda in the middle of the 20th century. Rumors persist that some populations of the species may survive in the area despite widespread deforestation and political unrest, but no sighting has been verified in more than two decades.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Lang's red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Democratic Republic of the Congo 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Langsredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Lang's red colobus is a type of red colobus monkey. Historically it had been treated as a subspecies of the Central African red colobus, (P. foai) but more recent taxonomies generally treat it as a separate species. //n Lang's red colobus lives in lowland rainforest in the northeastern portion of the Democratic Republic of the Congo between the Lualaba River and the Aruwimi-Ituri River. It eats leaves, fruit, flowers, buds and possibly seeds. Males have a head and body length of about 50 cm (20 in) with a tail length of about 66.5 cm (26.2 in). Females have a head and body length about 48.5 cm (19.1 in) with a tail length of between 44 and 66.5 cm (17.3 and 26.2 in).[2] Males weigh about 9 kg (20 lb) and females weigh about 7.7 kg (17 lb). //n A striking dark monkey with a mantle of red, Lang’s Red Colobus is native to the Congo. Primatologist Marc Colyn saw more than 360 dead Lang’s Red Colobus, as well as some living and thriving ones, near Kisangani, DRC in the 1980s. Since then, no researchers have been able to detect their presence. Two of these monkeys, killed by hunters, turned up in 2012. Since then, no other sightings have been recorded, despite dedicated searches of its former range, including one this year. Like many of the other red colobus species, it has been devastated by hunting and habitat loss.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Lomami red colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Lomamiredcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Lomami red colobus (Piliocolobus parmentieri) is a type of red colobus monkey from central Africa. Historically it had been treated as a subspecies of the Central African red colobus, (P. foai) but more recent taxonomies generally treat it as a separate species.//n The Lomani red colobus has a limited range in lowland tropical rainforest between the Lomani River and the Lualaba River in central Democratic Republic of the Congo. Its range extends as far south as the Ruiki River and the Lutanga River. It eats leaves, fruit, flowers, buds and possibly seeds. Males weigh about 9 kg (20 lb) and females weigh about 7.5 kg (17 lb).	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Black colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Blackcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The black colobus (Colobus satanas), or satanic black colobus, is a species of Old World monkey belonging to the genus Colobus. The species is found in a small area of western central Africa. Black colobuses are large, completely covered with black fur, and like all other Colobus monkeys, do not have a thumb. The species has faced large declines in population due to habitat destruction and hunting by humans, and was consequently listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List in 1994. //n The black colobus monkey is a large species with a head-body length of 50–70 cm and a long tail of around 80 cm. As in all Colobus species, the black colobus has a slender build and ischial callosities - tough pads of skin on the rump. There is little sexual dimorphism between the two sexes - adult males can weigh between 10–15 kg, whilst females weigh between 10–11 kg. The black colobus is covered in black fur apart from the ears and face, and has longer hairs on its cheeks and forehead. Unlike other species of colobus monkey, black colobuses have no white markings. The two subspecies of black colobus look very similar, although the fur of Colobus s. satanas is slightly longer and fluffier. There is currently not enough data to estimate the life expectancy of the species.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Angola colobus	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Angolacolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Angola colobus (Colobus angolensis), Angolan black-and-white colobus or Angolan colobus, is a primate species of Old World monkey belonging to the genus Colobus. //n Like all black-and-white colobi, the Angola colobus has black fur and a black face, surrounded by long, white locks of hair. It also has a mantle of white hair on the shoulders. The long, thin tail can be either black or white, but the tip is always white. There is a significant regional variation in the total amount of white on the body and the length of the fur. Animals that live in the mountains have longer, thicker fur than animals from the lowlands to protect them against the cold. //n The Angola colobus has a head-body length of 50 to 70 cm, with the males usually being larger than females. The tail is about 75 cm long, and the body weight varies between 9 and 20 kg.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	King colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Kingcolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The king colobus (Colobus polykomos), also known as the western black-and-white colobus, is a species of Old World monkey, found in lowland and mountain rain forests in a region stretching from Senegal, through Guinea-Bissau, Guinea, Sierra Leone and Liberia to the Ivory Coast. One of five members of the Genus Colobus which are the black-and-white colobuses. Among all African colobus monkey species, the King colobus (and the Western Red Colobus) is the westernmost species on the continent of Africa. It eats mainly leaves, but also fruits and flowers. Though it is arboreal, it eats primarily on the ground. It lives in small groups consisting of 3 to 4 females and 1 to 3 males, plus their young. These groups maintain distance from one another through territorial calling. //n The body is black, the limbs and fingers are long and the tail is white. There is a fringe of silvery hair around the face as well as long white 'epaulettes' on its shoulders. The king colobus can be distinguished from other members of the Colobus genus by the placement of its white markings. The king colobus has white only on its whiskers, chest, and tail, and its tail is not covered by a tuft.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Ursine colobus	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Ursinecolobus.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The ursine colobus (Colobus vellerosus, white-thighed colobus, Geoffroy's black-and-white colobus, white-thighed black-and-white colobus) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. //n The ursine colobus is quite distinctive, with predominantly black fur and lacking a white mantle. They have a black and naked face which is surrounded by a thick white halo of fur. The ursine colobus is further characterized by white patches on the thighs which vary in width and length. Like other species of colobus, the babies are born with an all white fur coat, which starts to turn black at around three months of age. In contrast to other species of colobus, they have slender bodies and ischial callosities, a hard thickened area of skin on the buttocks that allows comfortable sitting on branches. It has an all white tail which is longer than the body. They weigh between 9.9 to 10.3 kg (22 to 23 lb) for males and 8.3 to 8.7 kg (18 to 19 lb) in females with a body length of is 61 to 66 cm (24 to 26 in) in males and 61 to 64 cm (24 to 25 in) in females.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey>	<Name>	Mantled guereza	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Mantledguereza.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The mantled guereza (Colobus guereza), also known simply as the guereza, the eastern black-and-white colobus, or the Abyssinian black-and-white colobus, is a black-and-white colobus, a type of Old World monkey. It is native to much of west central and east Africa, including Cameroon, Equatorial Guinea, Nigeria, Ethiopia, Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda and Chad. The species consists of several subspecies that differ in appearance. It has a distinctive appearance, which is alluded to in its name; the long white fringes of hair the run along each side of its black trunk are known as a mantle. Its face is framed with white hair and it has a large white tail tuft. //n The mantled guereza is diurnal and arboreal, found in both deciduous and evergreen forests. It is an adaptable species that can cope with habitat disturbance and prefers secondary forest close to rivers or lakes. Although previously thought only to eat leaves, it also eats seeds, fruits, and arthropods. It is able to digest plant material with a high fibre content with its specialised stomach and may only eat from a few plant species at a time. It is preyed on by birds of prey and some mammals, such as the common chimpanzee and the leopard. //n The mantled guereza lives in social groups of three to fifteen individuals. These groups normally include a dominant male, several females, and the offspring of the females. It has a polygynous mating system and copulation is initiated with vocal communication. After a gestation period of just over five months, infants are born with pink skin and white fur, which darkens to the adult coloration by three to four months. The mantled guereza is well known for its dawn chorus, the males' 'roar' is a method of long distance communication that reinforces territorial boundaries. It also makes other vocalization and uses body postures, movements, and facial expressions to communicate. //n The mantled guereza is listed as Least Concern by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) because it is widespread – although it is locally threatened in some areas, the decline is not great enough to list it in a higher category of threat. However, one subspecies found in Kenya is listed as Endangered. It can survive well in degraded forests and in some areas it is more common in logged areas than unlogged ones. The mantled guereza is also threatened by hunting for bushmeat and for its skin.	</Info>	</Monkey>


</ArrayOfMonkey>