<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Red-shanked douc	</Name>
    <Location>	Vietnam, Southern Laos and possibly Northeastern Cambodia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Redshankeddouc.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The red-shanked douc (Pygathrix nemaeus) is a species of Old World monkey, among the most colourful of all primates. It is an arboreal and diurnal monkey that eats and sleeps in the trees of the forest. Like other doucs, the red-shanked douc is a long, slender monkey. The male has an average head and body length of 61 cm (24 in), and the female averages 54.5 cm (21.5 in) long, with a tail that measures 55.8–76.2 cm (22.0–30.0 in) long. Males weigh on average 11 kg (24 lb), and females 8.44 kilograms (18.6 lb). The red-shanked douc is the most colorful monkey among all species of primates. They are considered 'Queen of primates' thanks to their distinctive and unique appearance. Their forearms are white, upper legs black to grey and the lower legs a deep red while hands and feet are black. The monkey’s yellow-orange face and ears appear to be powdered with theatrical makeup, and the eyelids appear to be dusted with a powder-blue eyeshadow. Dark, almond-shaped eyes view the world, and from a modest nose, tiny nostrils inhale the fragrance of the forest habitat. Long, white whiskers (more generous in males) adorn the chin and frame the monkey’s alien-like face. A wide black band stretches across the monkey’s forehead. Belly and back are grey. There is a slight difference in rump markings between genders: the male has round white spots above the triangle of white on its rump, while the female does not. Males of all ages have a white spot on both sides of the corners of the rump patch, and red and white genitals. Shortly, the douc’s fur is a harmonious combination of the 5 colors: black, grey, white, brown-red and orange. Due to this fact, the species is also called the five-color douc. A baby douc has yellow-brown fur with black face. Between 8 and 24 months of age, the colors of the fur and face have changed gradually to form colors of the mature one.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black-shanked douc	</Name>
    <Location>	Cambodia and Vietnam	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blackshankeddouc.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black-shanked douc (Pygathrix nigripes) is an endangered species of douc found mostly in the forests of eastern Cambodia, with some smaller populations in Vietnam. This species is unique among the doucs in having a largely greyish-blue face. No global population estimate exists, although the Wildlife Conservation Society report an estimated 23,000 individuals present in Cambodia's Keo Seima Wildlife Sanctuary. Prior to the discovery of the significance of this population, the largest populations were believed to be in adjacent Vietnam, where the largest known population is around 500-600 individuals. They are primarily arboreal and their diet consists on leaves, of which they obtain most of their water.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Gray-shanked douc	</Name>
    <Location>	Vietnam	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Grayshankeddouc.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The grey-shanked douc langur (Pygathrix cinerea) is a douc species native to the Vietnamese provinces of Quảng Nam, Quảng Ngãi, Bình Định, Kon Tum, and Gia Lai. The total population is estimated at 550 to 700 individuals. In 2016, Dr Benjamin Rawson, Country Director of Fauna and Flora International - Vietnam Programme, announced a discovery of an additional population including more than 500 individuals found in Central Vietnam, bringing the total population up to approximately 1000 individuals. Grey-shanked doucs are very similar in appearance to P. nemaeus. They are light grey with a pale underside. Their feet and hand are black and their shins are a dark grey. The face is brownish orange on top with a white chin. Hair around the chin is white. The throat is white and lined on the bottom with an orange, brown collar. Males are slightly larger than females averaging 10.9 kg. Females average about 8.2 kg.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Golden snub-nosed monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	China	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Goldensnubnosedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The golden snub-nosed monkey (Rhinopithecus roxellana) is an Old World monkey in the subfamily Colobinae. It is endemic to a small area in temperate, mountainous forests of central and Southwest China. They inhabit these mountainous forests of Southwestern China at elevations of 1,500-3,400 m above sea level. The Chinese name is Sichuan golden hair monkey (四川金丝猴). It is also widely referred to as the Sichuan snub-nosed monkey. Of the three species of snub-nosed monkeys in China, the golden snub-nosed monkey is the most widely distributed throughout China. Snow occurs frequently within its range and it can withstand colder average temperatures than any other non-human primates. Its diet varies markedly with the seasons, but it is primarily a herbivore with lichens being its main food source. It is diurnal and largely arboreal, spending some 97% of its time in the canopy. There are three subspecies. Population estimates range from 8,000 to 15,000 and it is threatened by habitat loss.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black snub-nosed monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	China	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Blacksnubnosedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The black-and-white snub-nosed monkey (Rhinopithecus bieti), also known as the Yunnan snub-nosed monkey, is a large black and white primate that lives only in the southern Chinese province of Yunnan, where it is known to the locals as the Yunnan golden hair monkey (滇金丝猴) and the black-and-white snub-nosed monkey (黑白仰鼻猴). The common name, black snub-nosed monkey, is issued to Rhinopithecus strykeri, inhabiting in Northern Sino-Myanmar border. Coniferous and deciduous forests in the mountainous regions of Yunnan are the ideal terrain for these primates. It is threatened by habitat loss, and is considered an endangered species. With their unique adaptations to their environment, these monkeys thrive at extreme altitudes despite the below freezing temperatures and thin air. This primate's diet is mainly made up of the large amounts of lichens available in their region. Recent studies have provided more information on the black-and-white snub-nosed monkey, but there is still much to learn about them. Male and female black-and-white snub-nosed monkeys have no colorization differences, but do differ in sizes. Females weigh 20 lbs, while males are around 30 lbs. Adult black-and-white snub-nosed monkeys are identifiable by their gray/black and white fur. The underbelly and central facial zone are all white, while the rest of the body is a grayish black color. Their fur is extremely thick to protect them against below freezing temperatures. The monkeys are born with white fur that darkens with age. Another distinctive feature shared by both adults and babies, is their hairless and vibrant pink lips. These primates get the 'snub-nosed' part of their name from the absence of nasal bones. This is considered their most distinctive feature.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Gray snub-nosed monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	China	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Graysnubnosedmonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The gray snub-nosed monkey (Rhinopithecus brelichi), also known as Brelich's snub-nosed monkey, Guizhou snub-nosed monkey, and Guizhou golden monkey, is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to China, where it is known as the Guizhou golden hair monkey (黔金丝猴) or gray golden hair monkey (灰金丝猴). It is threatened by habitat loss. Of the three species of snub-nosed monkeys in China, the gray snub-nosed monkey is the most threatened, with a total population of less than 750 in around 20 groups surviving in the wild. Adults are covered with long, fine hair, generally grading from brown on its upper body to gray on its lower body, with a white patch between its shoulder blades. Its head, neck, and ends of its limbs are black, except for a golden brow. It has a golden chest, and chestnut fur on its inner knees and inner sides of its upper arms. Its face is bare bluish-white skin, pink around the eyes and mouth, and has a shelf-like brow and reduced nasal bones, giving it a snub-nosed appearance. Juveniles are shades of gray with patterns changing with age. Adult males are brighter colored than adult females, and have white skin on prominent nipples. Size data is limited, but two adult male specimens weighed 14.5 kg on average, and an adult female specimen weighed 8 kg, with adult length excluding tail ranging from 64–73 cm, and tail length ranging from 70–97 cm.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tonkin snub-nosed monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Vietnam	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>TonkinsnubnosedMonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The Tonkin snub-nosed monkey or Dollman's snub-nosed monkey (Rhinopithecus avunculus) is a slender-bodied arboreal Old World monkey, endemic to northern Vietnam. It is a black and white monkey with a pink nose and lips and blue patches around the eyes. It is found at altitudes of 200 to 1,200 m (700 to 3,900 ft) on fragmentary patches of forest on craggy limestone areas. First described in 1912, the monkey was rediscovered in 1990 but is exceedingly rare. In 2008, fewer than 250 individuals were thought to exist, and the species was the subject of intense conservation effort. The main threats faced by these monkeys are habitat loss and hunting, and the International Union for Conservation of Nature has rated the species as 'critically endangered'. The Tonkin snub-nosed monkey has a flattened face with a pink upturned nose, thickened pink lips and areas of blue skin around its eyes. The upper parts are black, the underparts creamy-white and there is an orange patch on the throat, particularly obvious in breeding males. The tail has a white tip. Its head-and-body length is 51 to 65 cm (20 to 26 in) and its tail 66 to 92 cm (26 to 36 in). Females weigh about 8 kg (18 lb) while males weigh 14 kg (31 lb). Juveniles are grey rather than black and lack the orange throat patch.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Proboscis monkey	</Name>
    <Location>	Borneo	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Proboscismonkey.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The proboscis monkey (Nasalis larvatus) or long-nosed monkey, known as the bekantan in Indonesia, is an arboreal Old World monkey with an unusually large nose, a reddish-brown skin color and a long tail. It is endemic to the southeast Asian island of Borneo and is found mostly in mangrove forests and on the coastal areas of the island. This species co-exists with the Bornean orangutan. It belongs in the monotypic genus Nasalis. The proboscis monkey is a large species, being one of the largest monkey species native to Asia. Only the Tibetan macaque and a few of the gray langurs can rival its size. Sexual dimorphism is pronounced in the species. Males have a head-body length of 66 to 76.2 cm (26.0 to 30.0 in) and typically weigh 16 to 22.5 kg (35 to 50 lb), with a maximum known weight of 30 kg (66 lb). Females measure 53.3 to 62 cm (21.0 to 24.4 in) in head-and-body length and weigh 7 to 12 kg (15 to 26 lb), with a maximum known mass of 15 kg (33 lb). Further adding to the dimorphism is the large nose or proboscis of the male, which can exceed 10.2 cm (4.0 in) in length,[9] and hangs lower than the mouth. Theories for the extensive length of their nose suggest it may be sexual selection by the females, who prefer louder vocalisations, with the size of the nose increasing the volume of the call. Nevertheless, the nose of the female is still fairly large for a primate. The proboscis monkey has a long coat; the fur on the back is bright orange, reddish brown, yellowish brown or brick-red. The underfur is light-grey, yellowish, or greyish to light-orange. Infants are born with a blue coloured face that at 2.5 months darkens to grey. By 8.5 months of age, the face has become cream coloured like the adults. The male has a red penis with a black scrotum. Both sexes have bulging stomachs that give the monkeys what resembles a pot belly. Many of the monkeys' toes are webbed.	</Info>
  </Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Pig-tailed langur	</Name>
    <Location>	Indonesia	</Location>
    <ImageUrl>Pigtailedlangur.jpg</ImageUrl>
    <Info>	The pig-tailed langur (Simias concolor), monotypic in genus Simias, is a large Old World monkey, endemic to several small islands off the coast of Sumatra in Indonesia. Its face is black, its fur is blackish-brown and it has a relatively short tail. It is a diurnal species, feeding in small groups in the rainforest canopy on leaves, and to a lesser extent, fruit and berries. Little is known of its natural history, but it is heavily hunted, its populations have been declining rapidly and the International Union for Conservation of Nature has assessed its conservation status as being 'critically endangered'. It has been included on a list of the World's 25 Most Endangered Primates. The pig-tailed langur is a large and rather heavily built Old World monkey, adapted to climbing with its long arms. Its fur is black-brown, and its hairless face is also black. It is the only monkey in the subfamily Colobinae to have a relatively short tail; the tail is only slightly furred and is only 15 cm long. The short nose is pointed upward. The pig-tailed langur reaches a full grown length of approximately 50 cm (20 in) and a weight of 7 kg (15.5 lbs). Traditionally, it has been placed in the genus Nasalis together with the proboscis monkey - a treatment still preferred by some.	</Info>
  </Monkey>

</ArrayOfMonkey>
  