<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfMonkey xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Monkey> <Name>	Barbary macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Northwest Africa, Gibraltar	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Barbarymacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Barbary macaque (Macaca sylvanus), also known as Barbary ape or magot, is a species of macaque unique for its distribution outside Asia. Found in the Atlas Mountains of Algeria and Morocco along with a small population of uncertain origin in Gibraltar, the Barbary macaque is one of the best-known Old World monkey species. Skull and brain, as illustrated in Gervais' Histoire naturelle des mammifères The Barbary macaque is of particular interest because males play an atypical role in rearing young. Because of uncertain paternity, males are integral to raising all infants. Generally, Barbary macaques of all ages and sexes contribute in alloparental care of young. Macaque diets consist primarily of plants and insects and they are found in a variety of habitats. Males live to around 25 years old while females may live up to 30 years. Besides humans, they are the only free-living primates in Europe. Although the species is commonly referred to as the 'Barbary ape', the Barbary macaque is actually a true monkey. Its name refers to the Barbary Coast of Northwest Africa. The Barbary macaque population of Gibraltar is the only such population outside Northern Africa and the only population of wild monkeys in Europe. About 230 macaques live on the Rock of Gibraltar. This population appears to be stable or increasing, while the North African population is declining.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Lion-tailed macaque	</Name>	<Location>	India	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Liontailedmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The lion-tailed macaque (Macaca silenus), or the wanderoo, is an Old World monkey endemic to the Western Ghats of South India. The hair of the lion-tailed macaque is black. Its outstanding characteristic is the silver-white mane which surrounds the head from the cheeks down to its chin, which gives this monkey its German name Bartaffe - 'beard ape'. The hairless face is black in colour. With a head-body length of 42 to 61 cm and a weight of 2 to 10 kg, it ranks among the smaller macaques. The tail is medium in length at about 25 cm, and has a black tuft at the end that is similar to a lion's tail, although this tuft is more pronounced in males than in females. Gestation is approximately six months. The young are nursed for one year. Sexual maturity is reached at four years for females, and six years for males. The life expectancy in the wild is approximately 20 years, while in captivity is up to 30 years.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Southern pig-tailed macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Tahiland, Malaysia and Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Southernpigtailedmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The southern pig-tailed macaque (Macaca nemestrina), also known as the Sundaland pigtail macaque and Sunda pig-tailed macaque, is a medium-sized macaque that lives in southern Thailand, Malaysia, and Indonesia. It is known locally as the beruk. Macaca nemestrina can reach a weight of 5–15 kg in large males. These monkeys are buff-brown with a darker back and lighter lower parts of the body. Their common name refers to the short tail held semi-erect and reminiscent of the tail of a pig.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Northern pig-tailed macaque	</Name>	<Location>	SouthEast Asia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>NorthernpigtailedMacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The northern pig-tailed macaque (Macaca leonina) is a species of macaque in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Bangladesh, Cambodia, China, India, Laos, Myanmar, Thailand, and Vietnam. Traditionally, M. leonina was considered a subspecies of the southern pig-tailed macaque (M. nemestrina), but is now classified as individual species. In India, it is found in south of the Brahmaputra River, in the northeastern part of the country. Its range in India extends from Assam and Meghalaya to eastern Aruanchal Pradesh, Nagaland, Manipur, Mizoram and Tripura. A detailed report on the ecology and behaviour of northern pig-tailed macaque has been published in 2008.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Pagai Island macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Mentawai Islands	</Location>	<ImageUrl>PagaiIslandmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Pagai Island macaque (Macaca pagensis), also known as the Pagai macaque or Bokkoi, is an Old World monkey endemic to the Mentawai Islands off the west coast of Sumatra. It is listed as critically endangered on the IUCN Red List due to its ever-shrinking habitat. Macaca pagensis formerly included the overall darker Siberut macaque as a subspecies, but this arrangement is polyphyletic,Pagai Island macaque males are generally larger than females. The males' body lengths range from 45–55 cm and females' body lengths are around 40–45 cm. Tail length is 13–16 cm for males and 10–13 cm for females. Males are also heavier, weighing around 6–9 kg while females weigh 4.5–6 kg. Their backs have a dark brown coloration, and chestnut to pale ochre on the sides of the neck, the front of the shoulders and the undersides of this species. Legs are brown and their arms, reddish brown. The faces of Mentawai macaques are furless and black-skinned with brown eyes. They have cheek pouches to carry food while foraging. leading to the two being classified as separate species. Both were formerly considered subspecies of the southern pig-tailed macaque.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Siberut macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Siberutmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Siberut macaque (Macaca siberu) is a vulnerable species of macaque, which is endemic to Siberut Island in Indonesia. It was formerly considered conspecific with the Pagai Island macaque (M. pagensis) which is overall paler in color, but this arrangement was polyphyletic.[3] Both were formerly considered subspecies of the Southern pig-tailed macaque (macaque nemestrina).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Moor macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Moormacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The moor macaque (Macaca maura) is a macaque with brown/black body fur with a pale rump patch and pink bare skin on the rump. It is about 50–58.5 cm long, and eats figs, bamboo seeds, buds, sprouts, invertebrates and cereals in tropical rainforests. It is sometimes called dog-ape because of its dog-like muzzle, although it is no more closely related to apes than any other Old World monkey is. It is endemic to the island of Sulawesi in Indonesia. The moor macaque is threatened mostly due to habitat loss from an expanding human population and deforestation to increase agricultural land area. The population is estimated to have decreased from 56,000 to under 10,000 from 1983 to 1994. In 1992, Supriatna et al. (1992) conducted an extensive survey and found only 3,000–5,000 individuals (2,500 mature) of the species. The survey estimated densities to be 25–50 individuals/km2 (18.7SD). Because several Sulawesi macaque species are endangered, information on ecology and behaviour is essential and conservation management plans are being conducted.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Booted macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Bootedmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The booted macaque (Macaca ochreata) is a macaque of the Sulawesi Island, Indonesia. This Old World monkey is diurnal and spends most of the day in the trees. It is 50–59 cm long plus a tail of 35–40 cm. The booted macaque feeds on figs, buds, invertebrates and cereals. Outside their native Indonesia booted macaques are found only at the Catoctin Wildlife Preserve and Zoo in Thurmont, Maryland. A family of booted macaques has resided there since the 1960s, and they are already into their fourth generation in captivity.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tonkean macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Tonkeanmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Tonkean black macaque or Tonkean macaque (Macaca tonkeana) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to central Sulawesi and the nearby Togian Islands in Indonesia. It is threatened by habitat loss. Widespread mining in central Sulawesi is believed to exacerbating the problems of habitat loss.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Heck's macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Hecksmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Heck's macaque (Macaca hecki) is a macaque of Sulawesi, Indonesia. This Old World monkey is diurnal. It feeds on fruits.	</Info>	</Monkey>
<Monkey> <Name>	Gorontalo macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Gorontalomacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Gorontalo macaque or Dumoga-Bone macaque (Macaca nigrescens) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is endemic to the island of Sulawesi in Indonesia.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Celebes crested macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Indonesia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Celebescrestedmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Celebes crested macaque (Macaca nigra), also known as the crested black macaque, Sulawesi crested macaque, or the black ape, is an Old World monkey that lives in the Tangkoko reserve in the northeastern tip of the Indonesian island of Sulawesi (Celebes), as well as on smaller neighboring islands. Locally known as yaki or wolai, its skin and hairless face is, with the exception of some white hair in the shoulder range, entirely jet black. Unusual for a primate, it has striking reddish-brown eyes. The long muzzle with high cheeks and the long hair tuft, or crest, at the top of the head are remarkable features. It has an 'apelike' appearance due to its almost non-existent, non-visible, vestigial tail stub of only approximately 2 cm (1 in). With a total body length of 44 cm (17 in) to 60 cm (24 in) and a weight of 3.6 kg (8 lb) to 10.4 kg (23 lb), it is one of the smaller macaque species. Its life expectancy is estimated at approximately 20 years in the wild.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Crab-eating macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Southeast Asia.	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Crabeatingmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The crab-eating macaque (Macaca fascicularis), also known as the long-tailed macaque, is a cercopithecine primate native to Southeast Asia. It is referred to as the cynomolgus monkey in laboratories. It has a long history alongside humans; they have been alternately seen as agricultural pests, sacred animals in some temples, and more recently, the subject of medical experiments. The crab-eating macaque lives in matrilineal social groups with a female dominance hierarchy, and male members leave the group when they reach puberty. They are opportunistic omnivores and have been documented using tools to obtain food in Thailand and Myanmar. The crab-eating macaque is a known invasive species and a threat to biodiversity in several locations, including Hong Kong and western New Guinea. The significant overlap in macaque and human living space has resulted in greater habitat loss, synanthropic living, and inter- and intraspecies conflicts over resources. The body length of the adult, which varies among subspecies, is 38–55 cm (15–22 in) with relatively short arms and legs. Males are considerably larger than females, weighing 5–9 kg (11–20 lb) compared to the 3–6 kg (6.6–13.2 lb) of females. The tail is longer than the body, typically 40–65 cm (16–26 in), which is used for balance when they jump distances up to 5 m (16 ft). The upper parts of the body are dark brown with light golden brown tips. The under parts are light grey with a dark grey/brown tail. Crab-eating macaques have backwards-directed crown hairs which sometimes form short crests on the midline. Their skin is black on their feet and ears, whereas the skin on the muzzle is a light grayish pink color. The eyelids often have prominent white markings and sometimes there are white spots on the ears. Males have a characteristic mustache and cheek whiskers, while females have only cheek whiskers. Crab-eating macaques have a cheek pouch which they use to store food while foraging. Females show no perineal swelling.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Stump-tailed macaque	</Name>	<Location>	South Asia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Stumptailedmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The stump-tailed macaque (Macaca arctoides), also called the bear macaque, is a species of macaque found in South Asia. In India, it is found in south of the Brahmaputra River, in the northeastern part of the country. Its range in India extends from Assam and Meghalaya to eastern Arunachal Pradesh, Nagaland, Manipur, Mizoram and Tripura. It is primarily frugivorous, but eats many types of vegetation, such as seeds, leaves and roots, but also hunts freshwater crabs, frogs, bird eggs and insects. The stump-tailed macaque has long, thick, dark brown fur covering its body, but its face and its short tail, which measures between 32 and 69 mm (1.3–2.7 in), are hairless. Infants are born white and darken as they mature. As they age, their bright pink or red faces darken to brown or nearly black and lose most of their hair. Males are larger than females, measuring 51.7–65 cm long and weighing 9.7–10.2 kg, while females measure 48.5–58.5 cm and weigh 7.5–9.1 kg. Males' canine teeth, which are important for establishing dominance within social groups, are more elongated than those of the females. Like all macaques, this species has cheek pouches to store food for short periods of time.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Rhesus macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Southeast, Central Asia 	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Rhesusmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The rhesus macaque (Macaca mulatta) is one of the best-known species of Old World monkeys. It is listed as Least Concern in the IUCN Red List of Threatened Species in view of its wide distribution, presumed large population, and its tolerance of a broad range of habitats. It is native to South, Central, and Southeast Asia and has the widest geographic range of all non-human primates, occupying a great diversity of altitudes and a great variety of habitats, from grasslands to arid and forested areas, but also close to human settlements.The rhesus macaque is brown or grey in color and has a pink face, which is bereft of fur. It has, on average, 50 vertebrae, a dorsal scapulae and a wide rib cage. Its tail averages between 20.7 and 22.9 cm (8.1 and 9.0 in). Adult males measure about 53 cm (21 in) on average and weigh about 7.7 kg (17 lb). Females are smaller, averaging 47 cm (19 in) in length and 5.3 kg (12 lb) in weight. The ratio of arm length to leg length is 89%.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Formosan rock macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Taiwan	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Formosanrockmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Formosan rock macaque (Macaca cyclopis), Formosan rock monkey, or Taiwanese macaque, is a macaque endemic to the island of Taiwan, which has also been introduced to Japan. Besides humans, Formosan rock macaques are the only native primates living in Taiwan. Rock macaques measure 50–60 cm and weigh 5–12 kg, generally females are smaller. Their tails are moderately long and measure 26–45 cm. This macaque is brown or gray in color. Like all other macaques, it has specialized pouch-like cheeks, allowing it to temporarily hoard its food. The gathered morsels are eaten sometime later, in safe surroundings.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Japanese macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Japan	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Japanesemacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Japanese macaque (/məˈkɑːk/; Macaca fuscata), also known as the snow monkey, is a terrestrial Old World monkey species that is native to Japan. They get their name "snow monkey" because they live in areas where snow covers the ground for months each year – no other non-human primate is more northern-living, nor lives in a colder climate. Individuals have brown-grey fur, red faces, and short tails. Two subspecies are known. In Japan, the species is known as Nihonzaru (ニホンザル, a combination of Nihon 日本 "Japan" + saru 猿 "monkey") to distinguish it from other primates, but the Japanese macaque is very familiar in Japan, so when Japanese people simply say saru, they usually have in mind the Japanese macaque. The Japanese macaque is sexually dimorphic. Males weigh on average 11.3 kg (25 lb), while females average 8.4 kg (19 lb).[7] Macaques from colder areas tend to weigh more than ones from warmer areas.[8] Male average height is 57.01 cm (22.44 in) and female average height is 52.28 cm (20.58 in).Their brain size is about 95 g (3.4 oz). Japanese macaques have short stumps for tails that average 92.51 mm (3.642 in) in males and 79.08 mm (3.113 in) in females. The macaque has a pinkish face and posterior. The rest of its body is covered in brown or greyish hair. The coat of the macaque is well-adapted to the cold and its thickness increases as temperatures decrease. The macaque can cope with temperatures as low as −20 °C (−4 °F).Macaques mostly move on all fours. They are semiterrestrial, with females spending more time in the trees and males spending more time on the ground. Macaques are known to leap. They are also great swimmers and have been reported to swim over half a kilometer. Lifespan is at the high end of what is typical for macaques, up to 28 years for males, and up to 32 years for females.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Toque macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Sri Lanka	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Toquemacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The toque macaque (Macaca sinica) is a reddish-brown-coloured Old World monkey endemic to Sri Lanka, where it is known as the rilewa or rilawa (Sinhala: රිළවා), (hence "rillow" in the Oxford English Dictionary). With age, the face of females turn slightly pink, prominent in the subsp. sinica.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Bonnet macaque	</Name>	<Location>	India	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Bonnetmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The bonnet macaque, also known as zati (Macaca radiata), is a macaque endemic to southern India. Its distribution is limited by the Indian Ocean on three sides and the Godavari and Tapti Rivers along with a related competing species of rhesus macaque in the north. Land use changes in the last few decades have resulted in changes in its distribution boundaries with the rhesus macaque, raising concern for its status in the wild. This Old World monkey is a diurnal animal. It is 35–60 cm long plus a tail of 35–68 cm. Males weigh 5.5 to 9.0 kg, females 3.5 to 4.5 kg. Captive monkey can live up to 35 years.The bonnet macaque feeds on fruits, nuts, seeds, flowers, invertebrates, and cereals. In southern India, this macaque exists as commensal to humans, feeding on food given by humans and raiding crops and houses. Two subspecies of bonnet macaques have been identified: M. r. radiata and M. r. diluta.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Assam macaque	</Name>	<Location>	South Souteast Asia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Assammacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Assam macaque or Assamese macaque (Macaca assamensis) is a macaque of the Old World monkey family native to South and Southeast Asia. Since 2008, the species has been listed as "near threatened" by the IUCN, as it is experiencing significant declines due to hunting, habitat degradation, and fragmentation. The Assam macaque has a yellowish-grey to dark brown pelage. The facial skin is dark brownish to purplish. The head has a dark fringe of hair on the cheeks directed backwards to the ears. The hair on the crown is parted in the middle. The shoulders, head and arms tend to be paler than the hindquarters, which are greyish. The tail is well-haired and short. Head-to-body-length measures 51 to 73.5 cm (20.1 to 28.9 in), and the tail is 15 to 30 cm (5.9 to 11.8 in) long. Adult weight is 5 to 10 kg (11 to 22 lb).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tibetan macaque	</Name>	<Location>	Tibet, China	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Tibetanmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Tibetan macaque (Macaca thibetana), also known as the Chinese stump-tailed macaque or Milne-Edwards' macaque, is found from eastern Tibet east to Guangdong and north to Shaanxi in China. It has also been reported from northeastern India. This species lives in subtropical forests (mixed deciduous to evergreen) at altitudes from 800 to 2,500 m (2,600 to 8,200 ft) above sea level. The Tibetan macaque is the largest species of macaque and one of the largest monkeys found in Asia. Only the proboscis monkey and the larger species of gray langur come close to match their size among Asian monkeys. Males are the larger sex, commonly attain a weight of 13 to 19.5 kg (29 to 43 lb) and length of 61 to 71 cm (24 to 28 in) long, with a maximum record weight of 30 kg (66 lb). Females, in contrast, weigh 9 to 13 kg (20 to 29 lb) and measure 49 to 63 cm (19 to 25 in) long. The stump-like tail adds only 4 to 14 cm (1.6 to 5.5 in), with females having a considerably shorter tail. The fur is well-suited to the species' cold environments being long, dense and brown on the back with creamy-buff to grey coloration on the underparts. Some adults are quite dark brown on the back, while others are basically a sandy yellowish-brown color. They have a prominent, pale-buff beard and long whiskers, but have a hairless face. The face is pale pinkish in males but is a more vivid, reddish-pink in females. The infants have silver-and-black fur that changes to its adult color at the age of two.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Arunachal macaque	</Name>	<Location>	India	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Arunachalmacaque.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Arunachal macaque (Macaca munzala), a relatively large brown primate with a comparatively short tail, is a macaque native to Arunachal Pradesh in northeastern India. Its species name comes from munzala ("monkey of the deep forest") as it was called by the Dirang Monpa tribe. It was discovered as a new taxon in 1997 by the noted Indian primatologist Anwaruddin Choudhury,but he thought it to be a new subspecies of Tibetan (or Père David's) macaque. It was described as a new species in 2004, when a group of scientists from the Nature Conservation Foundation, India reported it. It is the first species of macaque to have been discovered since 1903, when the Indonesian Pagai Island macaque was discovered. This monkey was reported on the basis of a good quality photograph as the holotype. In 2011, some researchers suggested, on the basis of morphological variation within the Assamese macaque, that it might be better treated as a subspecies. Subsequently, it was also discovered in Bhutan, where it was observed and photographed in the Trashi Yangshi area in 2006. The Arunachal macaque is compactly built and has a very dark face. It lives at high altitudes, between 2000 m and 3500 m above sea level, making it one of the highest-dwelling primates. It belongs to the M. sinica species-group of macaques, along with the Assamese macaque (M. assamensis), the Tibetan macaque (M. thibetana), the bonnet macaque (M. radiata) and the toque macaque (M. sinica).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Grey-cheeked mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Greycheekedmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The grey-cheeked mangabey (Lophocebus albigena), also known as the white-cheeked mangabey, is an Old World monkey found in the forests of Central Africa. It ranges from Cameroon down to Gabon. The grey-cheeked mangabey is a dark monkey, looking in shape overall like a small, hairy baboon. Its thick brown fur is almost black in its forest home, with a slightly rufus/golden mane around the neck. The sexes are similar, with the males slightly larger than the females. The grey-cheeked mangabey lives in a variety of habitats with the forests of Central Africa, it is generally thought to live in either swamp or primary forests, in some areas it has also been found in secondary forest as well. Some authors in the past have considered the species to be restricted to the forest canopy, however more recently habituated troops have been observed on the forest floor collecting food. It feeds primarily on fruit, particularly figs, taking other fruits seasonally, as well as shoots, flowers and insects. The grey-cheeked mangabey lives in groups of between 5 and 30 individuals. The groups have either a single male or (more usually) several, without a single dominant male. Young males leave the troop once they are adult and join other troops, whereas the females stay in the troop of their birth. If troops become too large they may split. Confrontations between troops are rare, as this mangabey will usually avoid other troops. Their territories cover several square miles of forest, and can both overlap with other troops and shift over time. Three subspecies of this mangabey were previously recognized. In 2007, Colin Groves elevated them all to species level, splitting one (johnstoni) into two species. 	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Black crested mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Blackcrestedmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The black crested mangabey (Lophocebus aterrimus) is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. It is found in Angola and Democratic Republic of the Congo. Its natural habitat is subtropical or tropical dry forests. It is threatened by habitat loss.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Opdenbosch's mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Congo	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Opdenboschsmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	Opdenbosch's mangabey (Lophocebus opdenboschi) is a species of crested mangabey in the family Cercopithecidae. It has also been treated as a subspecies of Lophocebus aterrimus. It is found in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (formerly Belgian Congo).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Uganda mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Unganda, Tanzania	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Ugandamangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Uganda mangabey (Lophocebus ugandae) is a species of Old World monkey found only in Uganda and in the Minziro Forest Reserve, just over the border in Tanzania. This crested mangabey was previously thought to just be a population of the grey-cheeked mangabey (L. albigena). Colin Groves upgraded the Ugandan population to the new species L. ugandae on 16 February 2007. This species is significantly smaller than the grey-cheeked mangabey, with a shorter skull and smaller face. 2008 was the most recent year in which the International Union for Conservation of Nature assessed the conservation status of L. albigena, describing it as being of least concern, and the status of L. ugandae has not been assessed separately. The Uganda mangabey is rather smaller than the grey-cheeked mangabey (L. albigena). It is less sexually dimorphic and has a smaller skull. Individuals from the east of Uganda have a yellowish-brown colour while those from the west are a slightly darker greyish-brown. The mane and breast are pale chocolate-brown and contrast more with the body colour than do the equivalent parts of the Johnston's mangabey (Lophocebus johnstoni).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Osman Hill's mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>OsmanHillsmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Osman Hill's mangabey (Lophocebus osmani), also known as the rusty-mantled mangabey, is a species of crested mangabey in the family Cercopithecidae with a restricted distribution in West Africa. Osman Hill's mangabey is a medium-sized lanky, arboreal, dark furred monkey. The sexes are similar in colour and markings but males are far larger than females, the size difference being especially marked in this species compared to the other members of the grey-cheeked mangabey superspecies. They have long, loose fur which is mainly blackish-brown, and a rufous tinged mane of longer hairs over the shoulders which is more noticeable in the males. The head shows a tuft on the crown and smaller tuft above the eyes, although these may not always be present, the cheeks are pale. The long tail is frequently held arched over the monkey's back. The two ischial callosities are bare and for a 'C' shapes which are complete in the male but often broken in the females. The bare skin on such places as the palms and soles is pink in newborns but darkens as the get older and is normally black by nine months of age. A single male specimen has been measured and he had a head and body length of 610mm and a tail length of 920mm.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Kipunji	</Name>	<Location>	Tanzania	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Kipunji.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The kipunji (Rungwecebus kipunji), also known as the highland mangabey, is a species of Old World monkey that lives in the highland forests of Tanzania. The kipunji has a unique call, described as a 'honk-bark', which distinguishes it from its close relatives, the grey-cheeked mangabey and the black crested mangabey, whose calls are described as 'whoop-gobbles'. Though it was originally thought to be a member of the Lophocebus genus genetic data later placed it as its own separate genus Rungwecebus. The kipunji is the first new monkey genus to be discovered since Allen's swamp monkey in 1923.The kipunji was independently discovered by researchers from the Wildlife Conservation Society, the University of Georgia, and Conservation International, in December 2003 and July 2004, making it the first new African monkey species discovered since the sun-tailed monkey in 1984.[1] Originally assigned to the genus Lophocebus, genetic and morphological tests showed that it is more closely related to the baboons (genus Papio) than to the other mangabeys in the genus Lophocebus, and that Lophocebus was diphyletic, meaning that species with differing genealogies have been mistakenly lumped together. Scientists have assigned it to a new genus, Rungwecebus, named after Mount Rungwe, where it is found. Zoologists were initially skeptical of the existence of the kipunji until its discovery, as traditional tales of the Nyakyusa people described the monkey as both real and mythical.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Hamadryas baboon	</Name>	<Location>	Horn of Africa, southwestern tip of the Arabian Peninsula	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Hamadryasbaboon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The hamadryas baboon (/ˌhæməˈdraɪəs/; Papio hamadryas) is a species of baboon from the Old World monkey family. It is the northernmost of all the baboons, being native to the Horn of Africa and the southwestern tip of the Arabian Peninsula. These regions provide habitats with the advantage for this species of fewer natural predators than central or southern Africa where other baboons reside. The hamadryas baboon was a sacred animal to the ancient Egyptians and appears in various roles in ancient Egyptian religion, hence its alternative name of 'sacred baboon'. Apart from the striking sexual dimorphism (males are nearly twice as large as females, which is common to all baboons) this species also shows differences in coloration among adults. Adult males have a pronounced cape (mane and mantle), silver-white in color, which they develop around the age of ten, while the females are capeless and brown all over. Their faces range in color from red to tan to a dark brown. Males may have a body measurement of up to 80 cm (31 in) and weigh 20–30 kg (44–66 lb); females weigh 10–15 kg (22–33 lb) and have a body length of 40–45 cm (16–18 in). The tail adds a further 40–60 cm (16–24 in) to the length, and ends in a small tuft. Infants are dark in coloration and lighten after about one year. Hamadryas baboons reach sexual maturity at about 51 mo for females and between 57 and 81 mo for males.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Guinea baboon	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Guineababoon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Guinea baboon (Papio papio) is a baboon from the Old World monkey family. Some (older) classifications list only two species in the genus Papio, this one and the hamadryas baboon. In those classifications, all other Papio species are considered subspecies of P. papio and the species is called the savanna baboon. The Guinea baboon inhabits a small area in western Africa. Its range includes Guinea, Senegal, Gambia, southern Mauritania and western Mali. Its habitat includes dry forests, gallery forests, and adjoining bush savannas or steppes. It has reddish-brown hair, a hairless, dark-violet or black face with the typical dog-like muzzle, which is surrounded by a small mane, and a tail carried in a round arc. It also has limb modifications that allow it to walk long distances on the ground. The Guinea baboon is the smallest baboon species, weighing between 13 and 26 kg (28.6–57 lbs). Their life spans are between 35 and 45 years. It is a diurnal and terrestrial animal, but sleeps in trees at night. The number of suitable sleeping trees limits the group size and the range. It lives in troops of up to 200 individuals, each with a set place in a hierarchy. Group living provides protection from predators such as the lion and various hyena species. Like all baboons, it is omnivorous, eating fruits, buds, roots, grasses, greens, seeds, tubers, leaves, nuts, cereals, insects, and small mammals. Because it eats almost anything available, it is able to occupy areas with few resources or harsh conditions. Its presence may help improve habitats because it digs for water and spreads seeds in its waste, encouraging plant growth. The Guinea baboon is a highly communicative animal. It communicates by using a variety of vocalizations and physical interactions. In addition to vocalizations to each other, this animal has vocal communications apparently intended to be received and interpreted by predators. Due to its small range and the loss of its habitat, the Guinea baboon is classified as "near threatened" by the IUCN. Baboon refers to the large-bodied primates with marked sexual dimorphism and having females and young that are dependent on males for protection.[3] Guinean baboons have a red tone to their fur, and are sometimes referred to as the red baboon. They lack hair on their hindquarters, and their faces are black with yellow-brown sideburns. Females' rumps are pink in color and males have a mane of fur around their heads and shoulders. A characteristic feature of baboons is their long molars and broad incisors. The long canines are evidence of sexual dimorphism in baboon species. Their forelimbs and hindlimbs are nearly equal in length and their digits on their hands and feet are relatively short and stout, making it difficult for them to climb. Baboons are one of the largest groups of monkeys and are sexually dimorphic in body size (meaning the males and females have differing body sizes). They can range in weight from 13 and 26 kg (28–57 lbs), making them the smallest of the baboon species.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Olive baboon	</Name>	<Location>	Central , West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Olivebaboon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The olive baboon (Papio anubis), also called the Anubis baboon, is a member of the family Cercopithecidae (Old World monkeys). The species is the most wide-ranging of all baboons, being found in 25 countries throughout Africa, extending from Mali eastward to Ethiopia and Tanzania. Isolated populations are also present in some mountainous regions of the Sahara. It inhabits savannahs, steppes, and forests. The common name is derived from its coat colour, which is a shade of green-grey at a distance. A variety of communications, vocal and non-vocal, facilitate a complex social structure. The olive baboon (Papio anubis), also called the Anubis baboon, is a member of the family Cercopithecidae (Old World monkeys). The species is the most wide-ranging of all baboons, being found in 25 countries throughout Africa, extending from Mali eastward to Ethiopia and Tanzania. Isolated populations are also present in some mountainous regions of the Sahara. It inhabits savannahs, steppes, and forests. The common name is derived from its coat colour, which is a shade of green-grey at a distance. A variety of communications, vocal and non-vocal, facilitate a complex social structure.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Yellow baboon	</Name>	<Location>	East Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Yellowbaboon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The yellow baboon (Papio cynocephalus) is a baboon in the family of Old World monkeys. The species epithet literally means "dog-head" in Greek, due to the shape of the muzzle and head. They have slim bodies with long arms and legs, and yellowish-brown hair. They resemble the Chacma baboon, but are smaller with a less elongated muzzle. Their hairless faces are black, framed with white sideburns. Males can grow to about 84 cm, females to about 60 cm. They have long tails which grow to be nearly as long as their bodies. Their life spans are roughly 20–30 years. Yellow baboons inhabit savannas and light forests in eastern Africa, from Kenya and Tanzania to Zimbabwe and Botswana. They are diurnal, terrestrial, and live in complex, mixed-gender social groups of eight to 200 individuals per troop. They are omnivorous with a preference for fruits, but also eat other plant parts, as well as insects. Baboons are highly opportunistic eaters and will eat almost any food they come across. Yellow baboons use at least 10 different vocalizations to communicate. When traveling as a group, males will lead, females and young stay safe in the middle, and less-dominant males bring up the rear. A baboon group's hierarchy is such a serious matter, and some subspecies have developed interesting behaviors intended to avoid confrontation and retaliation. For example, males have frequently been documented using infants as a kind of 'passport' for safe approach toward another male. One male will pick up the infant and hold it up as it nears the other male. This action often calms the other male and allows the first male to approach safely. Baboons are important in their natural environment, not only serving as food for larger predators, but also aiding in seed dispersal due to their messy foraging habits. They are also efficient predators of smaller animals and their young, keeping some animals' populations in check. Baboons have been able to fill a tremendous number of different ecological niches, including places considered adverse to other animals, such as regions taken over by human settlement. Thus, they are one of the most successful African primates and are not listed as threatened or endangered. However, the same behavioral adaptations that make them so successful also cause them to be considered pests by humans in many areas. Raids on farmers' crops and other such intrusions into human settlements have made baboons subject to organized exterminations projects. However, habitat loss is the driving force behind baboons' migration toward areas of human settlement.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Chacma baboon	</Name>	<Location>	 southern Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Chacmababoon.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The chacma baboon (Papio ursinus), also known as the Cape baboon, is, like all other baboons, from the Old World monkey family. It is one of the largest of all monkeys. Located primarily in southern Africa, the chacma baboon has a wide variety of social behaviors, including a dominance hierarchy, collective foraging, adoption of young by females, and friendship pairings. These behaviors form parts of a complex evolutionary ecology. In general, the species is not threatened, but human population pressure has increased contact between humans and baboons. Hunting, trapping and accidents, kill or remove many baboons from the wild, thereby reducing baboon numbers and disrupting their social structure. The chacma baboon is perhaps the longest species of monkey, with a male body length of 50–115 cm (20–45 in) and tail length of 45–84 cm (18–33 in). It also one of the heaviest; the male weighs from 21 to 45 kg (46 to 99 lb) with an average of 31.8 kg (70 lb). Baboons are sexually dimorphic, and females are considerably smaller than males. The female chacma weighs from 12 to 25 kg (26 to 55 lb), with an average of 15.4 kg (34 lb). It is similar in size to the olive baboon, averaging slightly higher in mean body mass, and of similar weight to the more compact mandrill, the males of which weigh on average about 1 kg (2.2 lb) more than a chacma baboon, the females weigh 3 kg (6.6 lb) less than the female chacma. While the mandrill is usually crowned the largest of all modern monkeys, going on total length and average (but not maximum) body weight between the sexes, the chacma baboon appears to be the largest extant monkey. The chacma baboon is generally dark brown to gray in color, with a patch of rough hair on the nape of its neck. Unlike the males of northern baboon species (the Guinea, hamadryas, and olive baboons), chacma males do not have a mane. Perhaps the most distinctive feature of this baboon is its long, downward-sloping face. The canine teeth of male chacma baboons have a mean length of 3.86 ± 0.30 cm (1.52 ± 0.12 in) at the time they emigrate from their natal troop. This is the time of greatest tooth length as the teeth tend to wear or be broken thereafter. The three subspecies are differentiated by size and color. The Cape chacma is a large, heavy, dark-brown, and has black feet. The gray-footed chacma is slightly smaller than the Cape chacma, lighter in color and build, and has gray feet. The Ruacana chacma generally appears to be a smaller, less darkly colored version of the Cape chacma.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Gelada	</Name>	<Location>	Ethiopia	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Gelada.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The gelada (Theropithecus gelada, Amharic: ጭላዳ, romanized: č̣əlada), sometimes called the bleeding-heart monkey or the gelada "baboon", is a species of Old World monkey found only in the Ethiopian Highlands, with large populations in the Semien Mountains. Geladas are actually not baboons (baboons are all taxonomic members of the genus Papio) but the only living members of the genus Theropithecus. Theropithecus is derived from the Greek root words for "beast-ape". Like its close relatives the baboons (genus Papio), it is largely terrestrial, spending much of its time foraging in grasslands. The gelada is large and robust. It is covered with buff to dark brown, coarse hair and has a dark face with pale eyelids. Its arms and feet are nearly black. Its short tail ends in a tuft of hair.Adult males have a long, heavy cape of hair on their backs. The gelada has a hairless face with a short muzzle that looks more similar to a chimpanzee's than a baboon's. It can also be physically distinguished from a baboon by the bright patch of skin on its chest. This patch is hourglass-shaped. On males, it is bright red and surrounded by white hair; on females, it is far less pronounced. However, when in estrus, the female's patch will brighten, and a "necklace" of fluid-filled blisters forms on the patch. This is thought to be analogous to the swollen buttocks common to most baboons experiencing estrus. In addition, females have knobs of skin around their patches. Geladas also have well developed ischial callosities. There is sexual dimorphism in this species: males average 18.5 kg (40.8 lb) while females are smaller, averaging 11 kg (24.3 lb). The head and body length of this species is 50–75 cm (19.7–29.5 in) for both sexes. Tail length is 30–50 cm (11.8–19.7 in). The gelada has several adaptations for its terrestrial and graminivorous (grass-eating) lifestyle. It has small, sturdy fingers adapted for pulling grass and narrow, small incisors adapted for chewing it. The gelada has a unique gait, known as the shuffle gait, that it uses when feeding. It squats bipedally and moves by sliding its feet without changing its posture. Because of this gait, the gelada's rump is hidden beneath and so unavailable for display; its bright red chest patch is visible, though.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Sooty mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Sootymangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The sooty mangabey (Cercocebus atys) is an Old World monkey found in forests from Senegal in a margin along the coast down to Ghana. While overall rated as Near Threatened, the eastern race lunulatus, also known as the white-crowned, white-naped, or white-collared mangabey (leading to confusion with the collared mangabey), is considered Endangered by the IUCN. The White-collared mangabey was declared its own species by the IUCN in 2016, but it retains the endangered conservation status. The sooty mangabey is native to tropical West Africa, being found in Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Liberia, Senegal, Sierra Leone and Ivory Coast. It lives in both old growth and secondary forests as well as in flooded, dry, swamp, mangrove, and gallery forests. The primate is arboreal and diurnal. They are omnivores whose diet includes primarily fruits and seeds, sometimes feeding on small animals. They live in social groups of four to twelve individuals, but occasionally groups as large as 95 individuals have been recorded.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Collared mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Collaredmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The collared mangabey (Cercocebus torquatus), also known as the red-capped mangabey, or the white-collared mangabey (leading to easy confusion with Cercocebus atys lunulatus), is a species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae of Old World monkeys. It formerly included the sooty mangabey as a subspecies. As presently defined, the collared mangabey is monotypic. The collared mangabey has grey fur covering its body, but its common names refer to the colours on its head and neck. Its prominent chestnut-red cap gives it the name red-capped, and its white collar gives it the names collared and white-collared. Its ears are black and it has striking white eyelids, which is why some refer to it as the "four-eyed monkey".[4] It has a dark grey tail that exceeds the length of the body and is often held with the white tip over its head. It has long molars and very large incisors. The average body mass for captive individuals ranges from 9 to 10 kg (20 to 22 lb) for males and 7.5 to 8.6 kg (17 to 19 lb) for females. Head-body length is 47–67 cm (19–26 in) in males and 45–60 cm (18–24 in) in females.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Agile mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Agilemangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The agile mangabey (Cercocebus agilis) is an Old World monkey of the white-eyelid mangabey group found in swampy forests of Central Africa in Equatorial Guinea, Cameroon, Gabon, Central African Republic, Republic of Congo, and DR Congo. Until 1978, it was considered a subspecies of the Tana River mangabey (C. galeritus). More recently, the golden-bellied mangabey (C. chrysogaster) has been considered a separate species instead of a subspecies of the agile mangabey. The agile mangabey has a short, overall dull olive-grey pelage. The bare skin of the face and feet is blackish. Males are 51–65 centimeters (20–26 inches) in length and weigh about 7–13 kilograms (15–29 lb), while the smaller females are 44–55 centimeters (17–22 inches) and weigh 5–7 kilograms (11–15 lb).	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Golden-bellied mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Congo	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Goldenbelliedmangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The golden-bellied mangabey (Cercocebus chrysogaster) is a social Old World monkey found in swampy, humid forests south of the Congo River in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. It was previously considered a subspecies of the agile mangabey (C. agilis).[1] Little is published about the species and its behaviour has only been studied in captivity.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Tana River mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Kenya	</Location>	<ImageUrl>TanaRivermangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Tana River mangabey (Cercocebus galeritus) is a highly endangered species of primate in the family Cercopithecidae. Some authorities have included the taxa agilis and sanjei as subspecies of this species, while others award these full species status. It is endemic to riverine forest patches along the lower Tana River in southeastern Kenya. It is threatened by habitat loss and degradation, which has increased in recent years. This species was, together with the equally endangered Tana River red colobus, the main reason for the creation of the Tana River Primate Reserve in 1978, but human encroachment within this reserve continues. Recently, it has been suggested that 20,000 hectares of the Tana River Delta should be transformed into sugarcane plantations, but this has, temporarily at least, been stopped by the High Court of Kenya.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Sanje mangabey	</Name>	<Location>	Tanzania	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Sanjemangabey.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The Sanje mangabey (Cercocebus sanjei) is a highly endangered Old World monkey of the white-eyelid mangabey group from the Eastern Arc Mountains in Tanzania. They are about 50–65 centimetres (20–26 in) in length, excluding the tail, and their body colour is greyish. Fruit makes up about 70% of their diet. They live in valley forests and on mountain slopes, but are mostly ground-dwelling, which makes them susceptible to hunting and poaching. Their habitat is being degraded, and the International Union for Conservation of Nature has assessed their conservation status as being "endangered". The Sanje mangabey is a medium-sized monkey; the sexes are similar in appearance but males are slightly larger than females. They are about 50–65 centimetres (20–26 in) long, excluding tail, and weigh about 7–9 kilograms (15–20 lb). The snout is grey while the skin on the rest of the face is pinkish or greyish, with a pale bluish border at the hairline, The eyelids and area under the eyes are particularly pale. The hair on the crown is longer than elsewhere and tends to have a parting or small whorl. Hairs on the crown and widow's peak have blackish bases and greyish-brown shafts. Hairs on the back, flanks and limbs have creamy grey bases and darker grey shafts, tipped with bands of yellowish-orange and black. The hairs on the underparts are long and pale yellowish-orange. The ends of the limbs and the hands and feet are dark grey. The bare area of skin under the tail is bluish-grey tinged with pink, and the ischial callosities are pink. The long, grey tail has a tuft of longer hairs at the tip.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Mandrill	</Name>	<Location>	Central Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Mandrill.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The mandrill (Mandrillus sphinx) is a primate of the Old World monkey (Cercopithecidae) family.[4] It is one of two species assigned to the genus Mandrillus, along with the drill. Both the mandrill and the drill were once classified as baboons in the genus Papio, but they now have their own genus, Mandrillus.[4] Although they look superficially like baboons, they are more closely related to Cercocebus mangabeys. Mandrills are found in southern Cameroon, Gabon, Equatorial Guinea, and Congo. Mandrills mostly live in tropical rainforests. They live in very large groups. Mandrills have an omnivorous diet consisting mostly of fruits and insects. Their mating season peaks in July to September, with a corresponding birth peak in December to April. Mandrills are the world's largest monkeys. The mandrill is classified as vulnerable by IUCN. The mandrill has an olive green or dark grey pelage with yellow and black bands and a white belly. Its hairless face has an elongated muzzle with distinctive characteristics, such as a red stripe down the middle and protruding blue ridges on the sides. It also has red nostrils and lips, a yellow beard and white tufts. The areas around the genitals and the anus are multi-colored, being red, pink, blue, scarlet, and purple. They also have pale pink ischial callosities. The coloration of the animal is more pronounced in dominant adult males. Both sexes have chest glands, which are used in olfactory communication. These, too, are more prominent in dominant adult males. Males also have longer canines than females, which can be up to 6.35 cm (2.50 in) and 1.0 cm, respectively.The mandrill is one of the most sexually dimorphic mammals due to extremely strong sexual selection which favors males in both size and coloration. Males typically weigh 19–37 kg (42–82 lb), with an average mass of 32.3 kg (71 lb). Females weigh roughly half as much as the male, at 10–15 kg (22–33 lb) and an average of 12.4 kg (27 lb). Exceptionally large males can weigh up to 54 kg (119 lb), with unconfirmed reports of outsized mandrills weighing 60 kg (130 lb) per the Guinness Book of World Records. The mandrill is the heaviest living monkey, somewhat surpassing even the largest baboons such as chacma baboon and olive baboons in average weight even considering its more extreme sexual dimorphism, but the mandrill averages both shorter in the length and height at the shoulder than these species. The average male is 75–95 cm (30–37 in) long and the female is 55–66 cm (22–26 in), with the short tail adding another 5–10 cm (2–4 in). The shoulder height while on all fours can range from 45–50 cm (18–20 in) in females and 55–65 cm (22–26 in) in males. Compared to the largest baboons, the mandrill is more ape-like in structure, with a muscular and compact build, shorter, thicker limbs that are longer in the front and almost no tail. Mandrills can live up to 31 years in captivity. Females reach sexual maturity at about 3.5 years.	</Info>	</Monkey>
  <Monkey>
    <Name>	Drill	</Name>	<Location>	West Africa	</Location>	<ImageUrl>Drill.jpg</ImageUrl>	<Info>	The drill (Mandrillus leucophaeus) is a primate of the family Cercopithecidae (Old World monkeys), related to baboons and even more closely to mandrills. The drill is a short-tailed monkey up to 70 cm (28 in) long, similar in appearance to the mandrill, but lacks the bright blue and red on the face of that species. It has high sexual dimorphism in weight, with males weighing up to 50 kg (110 lb) and females up to 12.5 kg (28 lb).The body is overall a dark grey-brown. Mature males have a pink lower lip and white chin on a dark grey to black face with raised grooves on the nose. The rump is pink, mauve and blue. Female drills lack the pink chin.	</Info>	</Monkey>




</ArrayOfMonkey>
 